<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="text.xsl"?>
<noticias>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/new-york-prison-break/index.html</url>
        <titulo>New York prison break: Source says search has gone cold</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T02:54:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Faith Karimi, Shimon Prokupecz and Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>A source says the escapees planned to kill the husband of prison worker Joyce Mitchell</highlights>
        <highlights>An official says the search for two convicted murderers has gone cold since last week</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Have authorities lost the trail of two convicted murderers who broke out of a New York prison?A New York state official briefed on the investigation told CNN on Monday that the search has gone cold since last week, when investigators found what they believe were several human tracks and a bloodhound possibly picked up a scent.There were promising clues last week, the official said, but since then, authorities have come up with little to point them toward the fugitives.Ten days into their search, authorities seem no closer to capturing Richard Matt and David Sweat. Despite the efforts of 800 law enforcement officials popping open trucks, peering into cars and scouring heavily wooded areas, New York's governor acknowledged over the weekend that the pair could be almost anywhere.Clinton County Sheriff David Favro said Monday that they could still be in the woods near the prison in upstate New York -- or long gone.And the prosecutor whose office brought charges against prison tailor Joyce Mitchell for allegedly aiding the escape said authorities can't say for sure whether anyone else was involved or whether Mitchell knows more than she's letting on.Meanwhile, the leads keep piling up -- more than 870 of them so far, according to New York State Police.They involve a mishmash of far-flung places: Vermont, Mexico, even a few miles from the Clinton Correctional Facility, the maximum-security prison in Dannemora, New York, from which Matt and Sweat escaped on June 6.Details about the fugitives' whereabouts may be scarce, but new details are emerging about Mitchell's relationship with the prisoners and the escape plot that one source says could have taken a deadly turn.Matt and Sweat had a plan to kill the prison tailor's husband, a source with detailed knowledge of the investigation said. It's unclear why, when they intended to do it and how much Mitchell actually knew about that plan.Investigators are looking into whether the two inmates threatened Mitchell to force her to help in the escape, the New York state official told CNN.Investigators believe Mitchell began getting cold feet executing the plan but possibly had agreed to be the getaway driver because of threats to her and her husband, the official said.Mitchell was having a sexual relationship with Matt, the source with detailed knowledge of the investigation said. And she'd also been investigated in the past for an inappropriate relationship with Sweat that led corrections officials to move him out of the tailor shop and keep them separated, Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie said.The prisoners might have been manipulating Mitchell from as far back as 2013, when the trio met, according to the prosecutor.Mitchell appeared in court Monday for a planned preliminary hearing, but that provided no answers.Wearing a black-and-white-striped prison jumpsuit and with her hands shackled to her waist, she didn't say anything during the brief hearing.Her attorney waived her preliminary hearing after a more than two-hour delay that was needed after her first court-appointed attorney had to drop out because of a potential conflict of interest.Mitchell has been in jail since last week, accused of helping the pair break out of their cells, and she will remain there unless she posts a $220,000 bond or $110,000 in cash.Mitchell supplied the inmates with various tools, including hacksaw blades, chisels, a punch and a screwdriver bit, according to court records.But that was not all, said Wylie, the Clinton County district attorney.After their escape, the two convicts planned to drive seven hours under the cover of darkness to a predetermined location, together with Mitchell, he said.Mitchell told investigators she was supposed to pick them up but got cold feet, Wylie said. The plan was to run off with the men after picking them up near a manhole where they'd emerge from a network of tunnels, according to Wylie."They were going to meet down by the power plant, drive -- I'm not going to say into the sunset, because it was after midnight and it was dark out -- but they were going to drive, potentially to an area that was about seven hours away," he said.Mitchell told authorities that the pair picked a destination, but they did not give her any specifics."That was the information that she was told by Matt and Sweat -- that it was about seven hours away," Wylie said.It's not clear if Mitchell has shared everything she knows, the prosecutor said."It's apparent that she's trying to be as truthful as possible, but in any of these investigations, we always find out that potentially somebody continues to hold things back for one reason or another, and that may be the case here," he said.If Mitchell knows more details about the escapees' location that she hasn't shared, Wylie said, authorities would love to hear it.After her change of heart, she began cooperating with police, authorities said."She did indicate one of the reasons why she didn't show up was because she did love her husband and she didn't want to do this to him," Wylie said.But the prisoners might have been manipulating Mitchell from as far back as 2013, when the trio met, he said.Mitchell has told investigators that Matt made her feel "special," a source familiar with the investigation said.State Department of Corrections officials had received a complaint about the relationship between Mitchell and one of the two escapees. The department didn't find enough evidence to support the complaint, but that does not mean there was no relationship, Wylie said.The governor said the state will have "zero tolerance" for any prison employee involvement."To the extent any state employee was involved in facilitating the escape, that is a crime in and of itself, and that will be fully prosecuted as a crime in and of itself," Cuomo said.Wylie also said Matt and Sweat could have had an alternate plan that didn't involve Mitchell."With the elaborate plan just to get out of the facility, it's very possible that they did have a Plan B," he said.More than 800 state, local and federal law enforcement officers are searching for the escapees, who left behind a sticky note with the words, "Have a nice day" before vanishing.According to Wylie, the pair may have left additional sticky notes."It's my understanding there were other notes or markers in the tunnel system," Wylie said. He didn't say what they contained.The manhunt for the convicts has expanded in Plattsburgh, in upstate New York, where authorities have shut a portion of State Route 374.Tracking dogs picked up their scent last week at a gas station in the town, where authorities believe they were rummaging through trash at a sandwich shop. But it's unclear when they were there.The local Saranac Central School District canceled classes last week as the search intensified. Classes resumed Monday, but with an enhanced police presence on campuses during school hours, New York State Police said. It said there will be no outdoor activities.Sweat was serving a life sentence with no chance of parole for the murder of a Broome County sheriff's deputy in 2002. Matt was sentenced to 25 years to life for the kidnapping and murder of a man in 1997.Mitchell may not face as much time, but she's looking at eight years behind bars if she is convicted.She pleaded not guilty Friday night to a felony charge of promoting prison contraband and a misdemeanor charge of criminal facilitation.CNN's Randi Kaye, Miguel Marquez, Julian Cummings and Sara Ganim contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612160345-prison-break-joyce-mitchell-prisoners-split-lead-06-12-jpg-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/12/us/gallery/new-york-prison-escape-manhunt-photos/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Manhunt for escaped New York prisoners</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-14T19:39:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor></autor>
        <texto>See photos from the manhunt for two convicted murderers who broke out of the Clinton Correctional Facility in Dannemora, New York, on Saturday, June 6.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150614143155-01-ny-manhunt-0613-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/prison-staff-inmates-relationships/index.html</url>
        <titulo>New York prison escape puts staff-inmate relationships in the spotlight</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T04:01:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Jethro Mullen and Dan Simon, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Hundreds of relationships between guards and inmates are documented each year</highlights>
        <highlights>"People find love in the strangest places," said the attorney of a guard who slept with killer</highlights>
        <highlights>Expert: Some people are drawn to the danger associated with convicts, others are lonely</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)The charges against a prison tailor accused of helping two convicted murders escape from a maximum security facility in upstate New York have cast a spotlight on relationships between inmates and correctional staff.The exact nature of Joyce Mitchell's ties to Richard Matt and David Sweat, the two murderers who are still on the lam, remains murky.A source with detailed knowledge of the investigation told CNN that Mitchell was having a sexual relationship with Matt. She has pleaded not guilty to charges of aiding him and Sweat.Hundreds of consensual sexual relationships between guards and inmates are documented each year in U.S. prisons, according to the Bureau of Justice Statistics.More than half of all substantiated incidents of staff sexual misconduct in U.S. prisons and jails were committed by female members of staff, according to a study by the bureau released last year.Prison authorities face the challenge of monitoring a complex web of interactions."I understand prisons run on a delicate balance, and having a good relationship between guards and the inmates, guards and the employees, employees and inmates is important," New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo said over the weekend."But there's a line. And when the line is stepped over, then action has to be taken."Some of the high-profile cases have drawn national attention.Nancy Gonzalez, a night guard at a federal prison in Brooklyn, was sentenced last year to a year in prison for having an unlawful relationship with Ronell Wilson, a convicted cop killer on death row."People find love in the strangest places," her attorney, Anthony Ricco, said during the case. "And people get together in the most difficult circumstances. We live in a society where these events happen. These types of cases are unusual, but they're not uncommon."Gonzalez gave birth to Wilson's child in 2013.In the upstate New York case, Mitchell's involvement with Matt and Sweat is still being investigated.She told investigators that she had planned to drive off into the night with the two men after they broke out of the prison. But she got cold feet, decided not to pick them up and later began cooperating with police, according to Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie.The manipulation of Mitchell, he said, may go as far back as 2013, when the trio met.The source with detailed knowledge of the investigation didn't say Monday how long Mitchell's alleged sexual relationship with Matt had lasted.She'd also been investigated in the past for an inappropriate relationship with Sweat that led corrections officials to move him out of the tailor shop and keep them separated, according to Wylie.Mitchell, who is accused of supplying the murderers with the tools to cut through prison walls, pleaded not guilty Friday night to a felony charge of promoting prison contraband and a misdemeanor charge of criminal facilitation.Family members have disputed the allegations that she helped the two murderers and planned to run off with them.Her husband and prison co-worker, Lyle Mitchell, is also under investigation, but has not been arrested or charged, authorities said. He worked in the maintenance department at the tailoring block where his wife was employed, Wylie said."She did indicate one of the reasons why she didn't show up was because she did love her husband and she didn't want to do this to him," Wylie said Saturday.The source with knowledge of the investigation told CNN on Monday that Matt and Sweat had a plan to kill Lyle Mitchell. But it's unclear why, when they intended to do it and how much Joyce Mitchell actually knew about that plan.One woman who did disappear with a convicted murderer was Bobbi Parker, the wife of a prison warden in Oklahoma.She and the inmate, Randolph Dial, went missing in 1994.More than a decade later, authorities found them living together in Texas.Parker said Dial had drugged and kidnapped her, but prosecutors said the two had fallen in love.She was found guilty of assisting his escape and served half of a one-year sentence.Experts say people, particularly women, can be drawn to criminals imprisoned for heinous acts for various reasons."There's a term, hybristophilia, which indicates that being around somebody that's very dangerous can be sexually arousing," said Joy Krause, who made a film about prison relationships, "Serial Killer Groupies: A Love Story.""Other people are just very lonely," she told CNN. "Some women like to have a long distance pen pal relationship. There are many, many reasons."The challenges that prison presents to physical intimacy serve as an attraction for some women."They get to be in love with them, pen pals with them, they can even marry them in prison but they don't have to have physical contact or sex with them," said criminologist Casey Jordan.Lengthy prison sentences also -- usually -- mean the inmate isn't going to disappear off anywhere."It's the ultimate in safety," Jordan said.CNN's Randi Kaye contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150609232803-sexual-relationships-between-inmates-guards-simon-pkg-ctn-00022917-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/hong-kong-arrests-explosives/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Hong Kong: Ten arrested, accused of conspiring to make explosives</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T02:52:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Tim Hume, Elaine Yu, and Wilfred Chan, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>A tenth person was arrested in Hong Kong on charges of conspiring to manufacture explosives</highlights>
        <highlights>Some in the group had links to a radical political group, police say</highlights>
        <highlights>Student pro-democracy leader Joshua Wong calls the arrests a "farce"</highlights>
        <texto>Hong Kong (CNN)Ten people, some with alleged ties to a radical political organization, have been arrested in Hong Kong, accused of conspiring to manufacture explosives, police in the Chinese territory say.At a news conference Monday, police said they had arrested five men and four women, ranging in age from 21 to 34, whom they described as members of a "local syndicate."A tenth person, a 58-year-old man, was arrested Monday afternoon at Lo Wu, a border crossing between Hong Kong and Mainland China.Police said their investigations showed that two men in the group were planning to test the powder of an explosive device. They raided a location in the territory's remote Sai Kung district Sunday evening, where they arrested the pair, seized chemicals and detonated explosives.Chemicals recovered during a subsequent house search were tested and found to be precursors of TATP, a highly volatile explosive thought to have been used in the 2005 London bombings and other terror attacks.Officers also found the chemical formula for manufacturing smoke grenades, police said.Police then swooped on others linked to the pair, and also seized air rifles, "V for Vendetta"-style face masks, political stickers and pamphlets, computers containing a sketch of an explosive device, and maps showing locations in Admiralty and Wan Chai -- districts where the city's government is based.Police would not say whether the maps identified targets where the explosives were intended to be used, or whether authorities were working with China's People's Liberation Army, which also has a base in Admiralty."There are maps that show the locations of Admiralty and Wan Chai, and there are possibilities that this group of people might want to do something in this particular location," said Au Chin-chau, chief superintendent of the police Organized Crime and Triad Bureau.Police said some members of the group claimed to be members of a local radical organization. Police would not name the organization.The arrests took place in an abandoned TV studio in Sai Kung. Now derelict and covered in graffiti, the studio is a popular place for photo shoots, teenager parties and paintball-like games with airsoft guns.News of the arrests came a day after thousands of pro-democracy protesters returned to Hong Kong streets, nine months after a demonstration that triggered 79 days of heated occupations in the semiautonomous Chinese city-state.A prominent leader of those protests, Joshua Wong, 18, said that there was a lack of evidence and that the arrests were a "farce" to smear localists, a group of hardline pro-Hong Kong, anti-Mainland demonstrators."Even if you wanted to storm the Legislative Council, you wouldn't make explosives to get in, it's not reasonable," he told CNN.He also questioned why any suspects, who have yet to be named, would readily admit they were affiliated with a local radical group."No matter who did it, the government successfully vilifies the localists," he said, adding that he did not identify as a localist.Ronald Leung, a spokesman for a hardline localist group, repudiated the idea of making explosives. But he speculated that if police allegations were true, it could reflect the level of frustration developing for a minority in the pro-democracy camp."It's sad, because it shows that the rule of the central and local governments has failed, and people have only become angrier," he said. "It is only inevitable that people will find more and more radical ways of resistance."Political tension has ramped up in recent days as Hong Kong's government prepares to table a Beijing-backed reform package ahead of Hong Kong's 2017 elections.The proposal, if approved, would allow Hong Kongers to cast votes for their next leader -- if the candidates are first vetted by China.But pro-democracy legislators, who have just enough votes to veto the bill, have sworn to do just that.Wong told CNN on Monday that the chance of it passing was "zero."CNN's Ivan Watson, Bex Wright, Vivian Kam and Agnes Chan contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615195759-hong-kong-conspiracy-explosives-lklv-watson-00010625-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/california-six-flags-roller-coaster-death/index.html</url>
        <titulo>10-year-old dies after riding roller coaster at Six Flags park in California</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T03:28:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</autor>
        <texto>(CNN)A 10-year-old who lost consciousness on a Six Flags roller coaster in Southern California has died.Jasmine Martinez was airlifted to the hospital Friday when she was found unconscious but still breathing after riding the Revolution roller coaster at Six Flags Magic Mountain in Valencia, California. She was pronounced dead on Saturday, but officials have not yet determined what caused her death, the Los Angeles County Coroner's Office said.The ride, which opened in 1976 and is billed by Six Flags as "one of the most famous and iconic looping roller coasters in the world," has been temporarily closed pending a review of the incident, amusement park officials said Monday."There is no evidence to suggest that this was in any way ride related," Six Flags Magic Mountain said in a statement expressing condolences to the girl's family. "We do not know if there was a pre-existing condition."More than 45 million people have safely ridden the ride since it opened, Six Flags said.CNN's Stella Chan, Cheri Mossburg and Tony Marco contributed to this report.</texto>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/washington-rachel-dolezal-naacp/index.html</url>
        <titulo>NAACP leader resigns; accused of lying about race</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T02:25:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Ashley Fantz, Ray Sanchez, Faith Karimi and Dana Ford, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>"This is not about me. It's about justice," Rachel Dolezal says in her resignation letter</highlights>
        <highlights>Dolezal's estranged parents have accused her of falsely portraying herself as black</highlights>
        <highlights>The story ignites a debate over race and identity</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Her statement was noticeable for what it was not.Rachel Dolezal, president of the NAACP chapter in Spokane, Washington, resigned Monday amid allegations of lying about her race.She stepped down in a statement that did little, if anything, to suppress the storm brewing around her and her family. Dolezal's parents, who are white, allege that she has been presenting herself as black when she is not.Dolezal did not address the allegations. She did not apologize."Please know I will never stop fighting for human rights and will do everything in my power to help and assist, whether it means stepping up or stepping down, because this is not about me. It's about justice. This is not me quitting; this is a continuum," she wrote in the statement posted on the NAACP Spokane Facebook page.Dolezal said that she's "waited in deference while others expressed their feelings, beliefs, confusions and even conclusions -- absent the full story."Shortly after the post appeared, some on Twitter weighed in, both in support of her and against what they considered Dolezal's deceptions.The president of the national NAACP also weighed in after Dolezal's resignation, issuing a statement and later speaking to CNN."Our members who looked up to her, appreciated her leadership, are pained, very disappointed," said Cornell William Brooks. "This is a distraction from the work."He added: "The NAACP is not concerned with the racial identity of our leadership but the institutional integrity of our advocacy. Our focus must be on issues not individuals."Dolezal's estranged parents have spoken to the media about her supposed misrepresentation."We are her birth parents," her father, Lawrence Dolezal, said Friday. "We do not understand why she feels it's necessary to misrepresent her ethnicity."CNN contacted Dolezal last week, and she declined an interview. She said she stands by her record of service.Her adopted brother, Ezra Dolezal, said she took him aside three years ago and asked him "not to blow her cover" about her alternate identity."She said she was starting a new life ... and this one person over there was actually going to be her black father," he said.Another adopted brother told a similar story of separation."She didn't consider them her parents and, you know, if we were to talk about then, they were Larry and Ruthanne, not Mom and Dad," Zach Dolezal told CNN.Dolezal has identified herself as at least partly African-American, but her Montana birth certificate states she was born to two parents who say they are Caucasian. The parents shared that document and old photos with CNN.She began identifying herself more with the African-American community in 2007, according to her parents.In 2002, Dolezal -- who studied at Howard University -- sued the historically black college claiming she was discriminated against on the basis of race, pregnancy, family responsibilities and gender.She specifically alleged that the decision to remove some of her artwork from a student exhibition was motivated by a discriminatory desire to favor black students over her. The suit was dismissed.Howard spokeswoman Rachel Mann said Monday the school considers the case closed and declined further comment.Separately, Dolezal has said she received threatening hate mail in the past, but the Spokane Police Department told CNN's Poppy Harlow that it dropped its investigation of the letters because of a lack of leads.The investigation was dropped before the controversy about her race became public.In the midst of that storm, Kitara Johnson, a member of the Spokane chapter of the NAACP, says her concern isn't that Dolezal may be white, but rather that she was perhaps untruthful about that."We have never called (whether she should lead) into question in terms of race," Johnson said. "Martin Luther King said we don't want to be judged by the color of our skin, (but) ... on the content of our character."CNN's Stephanie Elam, Paul Vercammen, Greg Botelho, Gary Tuchman, Tony Marco and Ralph Ellis contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615095243-rachel-dolezal-alone-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="middle-east">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/middleeast/yemen-aqap-leader-killed/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Top al Qaeda leader reported killed in Yemen</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T02:08:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Dana Ford, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Nasir al-Wuhayshi is believed to have died last week in Yemen's Hadramout region</highlights>
        <highlights>He was the No. 2 leader of al Qaeda globally and the head of AQAP</highlights>
        <highlights>"If it's true, it is a significant blow. Leadership matters," a U.S. senator says about the reports of al-Wuhayshi's death</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Top al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula (AQAP) leader Nasir al-Wuhayshi was killed Friday in a suspected U.S. drone strike in Yemen's Hadramout region, according to two Yemeni national security officials.Tweets from known AQAP operatives also spoke of al-Wuhayshi having been martyred, and of AQAP military commander Qasm al-Rimi (also known as Abu Hureira al-Sanaani) having been appointed as al-Wuhayshi's replacement.U.S. authorities are looking to confirm al-Wuhayshi's death, according to one U.S. intelligence official.Al-Wuhayshi was the No. 2 leader of al Qaeda globally and the head of AQAP. In a video that surfaced in April last year, the man who was known as al Qaeda's crown prince appeared brazenly out in the open, greeting followers.In a speech to the group, al-Wuhayshi makes it clear that he's going after the United States, saying: "We must eliminate the cross. ... The bearer of the cross is America!"The video showed what looked like the largest and most dangerous gathering of al Qaeda in years.Originally from Yemen, al-Wuhayshi assumed command of AQAP in 2009. He'd escaped a Yemeni prison in 2006, and had previously worked as a personal secretary for Osama bin Laden."If it's true, it is a significant blow. Leadership matters," Sen. Angus King, an independent of Maine, told CNN on Monday.King said the death would hurt al Qaeda, but stressed the group still poses a threat."This is a long, difficult struggle that we're engaged in, and it's going to require all kinds of tools," King said.Reports of al-Wuhayshi's death come shortly after U.S. planes carried out a strike inside Libya, purportedly killing a key terror figure in North Africa.The target was Mokhtar Belmokhtar, a veteran Islamist fighter, who is blind in one eye, affiliated with al Qaeda in North Africa, a U.S. official told CNN.The Libyan government said Belmokhtar was killed in the weekend strike, something that U.S. officials have not confirmed.CNN's Hamdi Alkhshali, Barbara Starr, Jomana Karadsheh and journalist Hakim Almasmari contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615170538-al-qaeda-leader-dead-lead-segment-00001003-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/us/einstein-letters-auction/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Einstein letters fetch more than $420,000 at auction</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T22:41:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Lauriel Cleveland, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>A letter about the connection between Einstein's special relativity theory and the atomic bomb sold for $62,500</highlights>
        <highlights>Topics of the 27 letters ranged from religion to the atomic bomb to infidelity</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)What did Albert Einstein think about adultery, the atomic bomb and God?At an auction last week, bidders shelled out just over $420,000 to own a piece of the Nobel prize winner's letters tackling these topics and other questions he faced during his lifetime.Organizers said the highlight of Thursday's auction -- which included 27 letters from Einstein -- was a 1945 letter about the connection between his special relativity theory and the atomic bomb.The genius physicist sent it to his son Hans less than a month after the bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and it sold for $62,500, according to the Profiles in History auction house in Calabasas, California.A 1939 communication from Einstein to President Franklin Roosevelt helped start the U.S. efforts to build an atomic bomb, but Einstein later said he regretted taking that step.In the letter to his son in 1945, Einstein wrote that his work and the bomb were "only very indirectly connected.""I already showed 39 years ago that pursuant to the special relativity theory, there is an equivalence between the mass and energy of a system or that both are only different manifestations of the same thing," he wrote. "I also noted that the energies released in radioactive decay are big enough to express themselves in an inaccuracy of the mass balance of radioactive reactions. That's all."The letters -- most written in German but some in English -- offer an inside look at Einstein's personal beliefs, like his thoughts about religion and the likelihood of the existence of God.In a 1945 letter to Guy H. Raner, Einstein described himself as an atheist."From the viewpoint of a Jesuit priest I am, of course, and have always been an atheist. ... It is always misleading to use anthropomorphical concepts in dealing with these outside of the human sphere -- childish analogies," he wrote, according to the auction organizers.Four years later, he wrote to Raner again. But this time, according to auction's organizers, his views seem to have shifted. He disparaged atheism and instead declared himself agnostic."I have repeatedly said that in my opinion the idea of a personal God is a childlike one," he wrote. "I prefer an attitude of humility corresponding to the weakness of our intellectual understanding of nature and of our own being."While many of the letters addressed his scientific work, religion and major political events of the time, Einstein also took time to share more personal thoughts with close friends and family.In another letter to his son Hans, he promised to send math problems to solve. And in a letter to a friend, he offered words of encouragement after learning of her husband's infidelity.In total, the letters generated $420,625, the auction house said."The auction was extremely successful," said Marc Kruskol, a spokesman for Profiles in History. "The Einstein letters sold for more than we expected."</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150611192620-einstein-letters-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/south-korea-mers-outbreak/index.html</url>
        <titulo>South Korea MERS death toll rises to 19; 4 more cases diagnosed</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T03:32:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By K.J. Kwon and Madison Park, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Three more patients have died in South Korea's MERS outbreak, bringing the toll to 19</highlights>
        <highlights>Four more cases were announced Tuesday, bringing the total number to 154</highlights>
        <highlights>16 of those patients are in an "unstable" condition, according to health authorities</highlights>
        <texto>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)South Korean officials announced three more deaths in the country's MERS outbreak Tuesday, raising the total death toll to 19.Four new cases of Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) were also announced, bringing the total number to 154 -- 16 of whom are in an "unstable" condition, according to South Korea's Ministry of Health.The number of people under quarantine in South Korea, both in their own homes or in quarantine facilities, rose by 370 from Monday to 5,586.A day earlier, there had been a sign of a possible return to normalcy, as thousands of schools across South Korea re-opened after closures due to the deadly outbreak.But it came with heightened awareness; children's temperatures were monitored in classrooms and teachers warned students to practice personal hygiene and frequently wash their hands.Not all schools have reopened; 440 remain shut as officials seek to stop the spread of MERS.The World Health Organization had recommended re-opening institutions last week because transmission of the virus had not been linked to schools.The outbreak has sparked international concern, stalled the nation's economy and resulted in over 100,000 canceled tourist visits to the country. Korea's department store sales tumbled 16.5% compared with the same period last year and retail shops also decreased 3.4%, according to the Ministry of Strategy and Finance.The ongoing situation has put Korean authorities under scrutiny for their inability to contain MERS cases and President Park Geun-hye has seen her approval ratings plummet.The Ministry of Health will hold an emergency meeting with the WHO Tuesday evening.In a news conference Monday, the Ministry of Health announced that a special task force had been sent to South Korea's second largest city, Busan, after learning that one of the most recently diagnosed MERS patient had visited several hospitals and clinics in the area."We are doing our best to stop the spread of MERS," said the Korean minister of health. "We are analyzing the CCTV with the help of Busan police," referring to tracking down who had been at the hospitals.On Sunday, a 61-year-old man died in a Busan hospital with MERS.South Korean health officials along with a WHO team said this weekend, that the outbreak was slowing, but additional cases were expected.Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia has recorded five cases of MERS in the past week, the official state-run Saudi press agency said Sunday, citing a weekly Ministry of Health statement. It included one death of a 73-year-old man who died in the city of Turaba and had a pre-existing condition.The strain of coronavirus that causes MERS was first identified in 2012 in Saudi Arabia, according to the WHO.The man believed to be "patient zero" in the current outbreak in South Korea visited Saudi Arabia in May, along with three other Middle Eastern countries. That 68-year-old patient went from facility-to-facility near or around Seoul before getting properly diagnosed. It triggered the hospital-based transmission of MERS in South Korea.The South Korean outbreak is the largest outside of Saudi Arabia -- over 5,000 people remain in quarantine.In Seoul, Samsung Medical Center -- one of the city's hospitals that has counted many of the nation's MERS cases among its patients and visitors -- announced Sunday that it will suspend all surgical procedures except for emergency surgery "to fully focus on responding to MERS."More than 50 confirmed MERS cases have been traced back to the medical center, according to the center's website.The medical center, located in Seoul's glitzy Gangnam district and considered one of the most prominent hospitals in the capital, issued an apology for its handling of MERS."We sincerely apologize with our heads bent to the people for causing great concern as Samsung Medical Center became the center (of) the spread of MERS," hospital President Song Jae-hoon said.CNN's K.J. Kwon reported from Seoul. CNN's Anas Hamdan reported from Atlanta. Journalists Jung-eun Kim and Han Sol, and CNN's Kay Guerrero and Khushbu Shah contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615113936-south-korea-mers-theatre-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/us/nc-shark-attacks/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Two teens lose limbs in separate shark attacks at North Carolina beach</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16T02:48:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Kevin Conlon and Janet DiGiacomo, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Circumstances suggest both attacks may have been by a single shark, researcher says</highlights>
        <highlights>Two teens lose arms in separate shark attacks at same beach</highlights>
        <highlights>Attacks occurred within 90 minutes of each other</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)A 13-year-old girl and 16-year-old boy each lost an arm Sunday in separate shark attacks at the same North Carolina beach.Oak Island Mayor Betty Wallace told CNN that the female swimmer was attacked first, around 4:15 p.m. Less than 90 minutes later, as responders were still tending to her, the boy was attacked.It is not typical to shut down the beach or evacuate the water after a shark attack, town spokesman Kyle Thomas said.Both victims were airlifted to New Hanover Regional Medical Center in Wilmington. Both arrived in critical condition, according to hospital spokeswoman Martha Harlan.Harlan said each has had an arm amputated -- his below the shoulder, hers at the elbow. The girl also sustained serious tissue damage to her leg, according to Harlan.Both patients -- whose names are not being released -- have since been upgraded to fair condition.Wallace told CNN that shark attacks are so rare at Oak Island -- a beach town on the state's southernmost coast -- that she couldn't remember one occurring before Sunday.Witness Jason Hunter told CNN affiliate WWAY that the shark involved in the attack on the boy was 7 or 8 feet long.Both incidents occurred at high tide in the vicinity of Ocean Crest Pier, a popular destination among beachgoers."At the pier this time of year, I'm sure the beach was packed," said Wallace.The pier is also a popular spot to fish from, meaning there was likely bait in the water that could have attracted sharks.A 911 call released by Brunswick County captured the drama of the first attack.The dispatcher tells the caller, "we're getting help on the way. Are any of the fingers completely amputated?"The response: "It looks like her entire hand is gone,"Marie Hildreth, an off-duty EMT, happened to be vacationing at the beach, and ran to provide aid after hearing someone yelled "shark!"Seeing that the girl was hemorrhaging, Hildreth decided to put tourniquets on two different limbs, she told CNN's Anderson Cooper.She used what was available: a string from a boogie board and a string from a tent.One of the first on-duty paramedics at the scene, Tracy Carnes, credited bystanders' help for saving the girl's life."The outpouring of help from the bystanders was amazing," she told CNN's Erin Burnett. "The tourniquets were in place by the time I got there."The Oak Island beaches remained open on Monday, but in contrast to most summer days, virtually no one was in the water.The beach was not empty, but nearly everyone stayed on dry land.This area, which has mostly houses and no highrises, does not attract the throngs of visitors that more touristy beaches do. It's mostly a haven for families who come and rent houses and enjoy the beach. But even by local standards, the beaches on Monday were quite desolate.Helicopters from the sheriff's office monitored the coastline.Oak Island, south of Wilmington, is home to about 7,000 residents, but tourists swell the population to about 25,000 during the summer, Anselmo said.About four or five people are bitten by sharks on North Carolina beaches each year, said George Burress, an ichthyologist and fisheries biologist with the Florida Museum of Natural History. The incidents usually involve smaller sharks, he said."Having a series of injuries so close to each other in time and space makes this unusual," he said. "Two in one day very close to each other suggests that there's a focused problem. It might suggest a single shark has been involved."He suspects the predator could be either a bull or tiger shark, both of which are undaunted by larger prey, he said."They may have interpreted the humans as being appropriate in size and behavior to give it a shot," the researcher said.Only three times in the four decades that he's been studying sharks has Burgess seen attacks happen "so closely in time and space," he said. The other incidents occurred in Egypt and Florida.Any number of factors, including an abundance of fish or nesting turtles, could draw sharks to the area, Burgess said.Burgess urged people to remember that despite the horrific nature of Sunday's attacks, shark attacks are unusual. Last year saw 72 attacks, only three of which were fatal, he said."Considering the billions of hours we spend in the sea," he said, "it's clear that shark attacks aren't common."CNN's Mary Helen Moore, Eliott C. McLaughlin, Stephanie Gallman and Shawn Nottingham contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615202832-nc-teen-shark-bites-erin-responders-interview-00005803-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="europe">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/pope-climate-change-encyclical/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Pope's message on climate change leaked</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T22:30:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By CNN Staff</autor>
        <highlights>L'Espresso publishes a leaked version of the Pope's letter on the environment</highlights>
        <highlights>The Vatican says the leaked document is a draft and asks journalists not to publish it</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Days before it was to be published to great fanfare, a leaked draft of Pope Francis' eagerly awaited letter on the environment was published Monday by an Italian magazine.L'Espresso published the 192-page document in Italian online. A Vatican embargo on the letter, called an encyclical, was set to lift at 6 a.m. ET on Thursday.In a statement, the Vatican said that the leaked document is only a draft and the rules of the embargo remain in place."We ask journalists to respect professional standards, which call for the official publication of the final text," the Vatican said.Derived from the Greek word for "circle," a papal encyclical is a letter from the pope to Catholic clergy and laypeople around the world. Often, the letters clarify Catholic doctrine, reiterate points of dogma and address contemporary issues through the light of church teachings.Pope Francis, though, has said he hopes his letter will reach a wider audience, including world leaders meeting for several key environmental summits this year.The upcoming encyclical will be the first to focus exclusively on creation care, the Christian idea that God gave humans the Earth to cultivate, not conquer. It's also the first entirely written by Francis.In a nod to his namesake, St. Francis, the Pope has titled his upcoming encyclical "Laudato Si." The archaic Italian phrase, which means "Be praised," is borrowed from the patron saint of ecology's 13th-century song, "Canticle of the Sun."Months before its publication, the encyclical has drawn criticism from conservatives and climate change skeptics, who urged the Pope not to put his moral weight behind such a controversial cause.From the first days of his papacy, Francis has preached about the importance of the environment, not only as a scientific concern but also a moral one. In his first homily as pontiff, Francis called six times during the short sermon for humans to protect creation.Vatican advisers have said "Laudato Si" will not be a white paper delving deeply into policy prescriptions. But neither is Francis likely to ignore the opinion of most scientists about how human activities contribute to climate change.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150209155621-01-pope-quote-0209-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/asia/north-korea-soldier-defection/index.html</url>
        <titulo>North Korean soldier walks across border to defect, South says</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T23:36:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Jethro Mullen, K.J. Kwon and Jung-eun Kim, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>North Korea tells the South it will release two South Koreans detained last month</highlights>
        <highlights>South Korean defense official: Soldier from North walked across the sensitive border</highlights>
        <highlights>Defections directly from North to South Korea are rare but not unheard of</highlights>
        <texto>Seoul, South Korea (CNN)A North Korean soldier defected to South Korea on Monday across the heavily fortified border that separates the two countries, South Korean authorities said.The soldier crossed the Military Demarcation Line on foot from the eastern North Korean province of Gangwon, said a South Korean Defense Ministry official, who declined to be identified.Further details on the circumstances of the defection weren't immediately available. There was no reaction to the news on North Korean state media.The border between North and South Korea is considered to be the most heavily militarized in the world. The two countries technically remain at war, because the 1950-53 Korean War ended in an armed truce and not a peace treaty.North Korean soldiers have occasionally made it across the highly sensitive zone in the past.In 2012, one managed to cross the border unnoticed and knock on the door of a South Korean barracks, embarrassing the South Korean military and prompting a public apology from the defense minister at the time for the security lapse.But defections directly across the border from North to South Korea are rare.Most people attempt to flee the impoverished, oppressively ruled North by crossing the more open border into China and then trying to make their way to South Korea through other countries.More than 26,000 refugees from the North have reached the South since the end of the Korean War, according to the Unification Ministry in Seoul.The vast majority of them arrived during the past 15 years. But defection has become harder in recent years, the Unification Ministry says, and the number of people doing it has fallen significantly since Kim Jong Un succeeded his father as the North Korean leader.Separately, North Korea on Monday said it was willing to hold talks with the South -- but with conditions attached."If an atmosphere of trust and reconciliation is created between North and South Korea, there is no reason not to hold dialogue and negotiation between the two sides," a North Korean government statement carried by state media said.The conditions it set out included its often repeated call for South Korea to stop holding joint military exercises with the United States, a request that Seoul and Washington have consistently dismissed.Pyongyang also told Seoul on Monday that it plans to release two South Korean citizens this week, according to the South Korean Unification Ministry.North Korea said the two South Koreans -- a man in his late 50s with the surname Lee, and a woman in her early 50s with the surname Jin -- illegally entered North Korea on May 11. North Korea detained them the same month.The South Korean government said it believes the two went missing while traveling in China near the North Korean border. It expects to collect them Wednesday morning at Panmunjom, the "truce village" that straddles the border between the two Koreas.CNN's K.J. Kwon and journalist Jung-eun Kim reported from Seoul, and CNN's Jethro Mullen wrote from Hong Kong.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615180234-north-korea-soldier-defects-todd-snt-sit-room-00000913-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="africa">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/africa/south-africa-summit-icc-omar-al-bashir-arrest/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Sudan's leader leaves South Africa before court orders arrest</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T22:51:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Don Melvin and Eliott C. McLaughlin, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Court orders Omar al-Bashir's arrest, but he had already left the country</highlights>
        <highlights>Lawyers' group had demanded arrest on charges of war crimes</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir, a man accused of war crimes and genocide, has left South Africa one step ahead of the law.Al-Bashir left the country Monday just as a South African High Court decided to order his arrest.The human rights group that had petitioned the court to order al-Bashir's arrest, the Southern Africa Litigation Centre, said in a statement it was disappointed that the government allowed the Sudanese President to leave before the ruling.Judge Hans Fabricius had ruled Sunday that al-Bashir had to stay in South Africa while a court considered whether he should be arrested. The judge also ordered all ports in the country to prevent the Sudanese leader from leaving.But lawyers arguing in court for al-Bashir's arrest warned, in advance, that the ports of entry and exit were not obeying the judge's order."Being an organisation committed to the rule of law, SALC is encouraged by the Court's order and the independence of the judicial process," said Kaajal Ramjathan-Keogh, the group's director. "The rule of law, however, is only as strong as the government which enforces it. Home Affairs have allowed a fugitive from justice to slip through its fingers, compounding the suffering of the victims of these grave crimes."Al-Bashir's departure was confirmed by the South African and Sudanese governments.Sudan's state news agency, SUNA, reported that Sudanese Foreign Minister Ibrahim Ghandour would hold a news conference at the airport Monday evening "following return of the President of the Republic."It is unclear in light of the judge's order what help al-Bashir might have received, and from whom. His plane had been relocated earlier from Tambo International Airport, near Johannesburg, to Waterkloof military base, south of Pretoria.And sometime after that, the alleged war criminal went to the military base and slipped through the net.His departure came as the North Gauteng High Court in Pretoria was considering a request by the International Criminal Court to arrest him on charges of war crimes, crimes against humanity and genocide.The ICC charges against al-Bashir stem from the conflict in the Darfur region in western Sudan, which began in 2003. The government of Sudan has been accused of repression and ethnic cleansing of Darfur's non-Arab population.Al-Bashir had been in South Africa attending a two-day summit of African Union leaders.Fabricius, the judge, said Sunday that he wanted to determine whether it was legally acceptable for Pretoria to allow al-Bashir to visit South Africa without arresting him -- and key in that decision would be determining if the South African Cabinet's decision not to comply with the ICC demand could trump an international treaty, South Africa's Mail &amp; Guardian newspaper reported.Earlier Monday, when al-Bashir's whereabouts were still unclear, the chairman of South Africa's Portfolio Committee on International Relations and Cooperation, Siphosezwe Masango, said he was concerned about the Sudanese President's possible arrest."This is an opportunistic act only meant to pit African leaders against each other in the name of international law," Masango said in a statement. He urged the leaders gathered for the summit to concentrate instead on regional trade, xenophobia and the development of Africa's infrastructure.He said the ICC appeared to target African leaders and, if the trend continued, his committee might have to recommend that the government re-examine South Africa's membership in the international court.But the U.N.'s high commissioner for human rights, Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein, warned that member states had to follow ICC rules."It is of deep concern to me and my office when court orders are issued by the ICC in respect of the serving head of state of Sudan, and state parties to the Rome Statute openly flout them," he said Monday at a meeting of the Human Rights Council in Geneva, Switzerland.The Rome Statute was a treaty that established the International Criminal Court."In this regard, we await the ruling of the Pretoria High Court this morning, as it assesses the request submitted by the ICC," he said.Sidiki Kaba, the Senegalese justice minister who serves as president of the assembly of states parties to the Rome Statute, expressed his "deep concern about the negative consequences for the court in case of nonexecution of the warrants by States Parties and, in this regard, urges them to respect their obligations to cooperate with the Court."South Africa, Kaba said in a statement, should "spare no effort" to arrest al-Bashir.South Africa had twice before threatened to arrest al-Bashir -- in 2009 before President Jacob Zuma's inauguration and in 2010 before the World Cup, according to the Southern Africa Litigation Centre. He attended neither event, according to news reports.Arrest warrants from 2009 and 2010 outline the case against al-Bashir and allege that during the Darfur conflict he ordered the military, police and Janjaweed militia to attack three ethnic groups deemed sympathetic to rebel outfits with "the specific intent to destroy in part" those groups.As part of that campaign, the warrants say, the Sudanese President ordered the rape, murder and torture of civilians and the razing of villages.The United Nations has estimated that as many as 300,000 people have been killed in the Darfur conflict since 2003, a tally the Sudanese government says is inflated. Another 7 million are in need of humanitarian assistance, the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees estimates.Last week, the U.N. assistant secretary-general for peacekeeping operations told the Security Council that the ongoing violence in Darfur was having a "devastating" impact on civilians. More than 78,000 civilians have been displaced this year, the U.N. reports.CNN's Brent Swails and Tony Wende contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150614114753-omar-al-bashir-au-summit-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/asia/china-no-frills-weddings/index.html</url>
        <titulo>No frills? Chinese say 'I do' to creative -- and cheaper -- weddings</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T10:15:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Steven Jiang, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Average Chinese wedding now costs $20,000</highlights>
        <highlights>But some young Chinese don't want to shoulder the expense</highlights>
        <highlights>Instead, they favor simpler "naked marriages"</highlights>
        <texto>Beijing (CNN)Shiny rings, white gowns and luxury cars filled the mammoth national convention center, next to the Chinese capital's Olympic Bird's Nest stadium, one recent weekend.Armed with balloons, teddy bears and goody bags filled with coupons, throngs of salespeople stood outside their booths, shoving free gifts into the hands of visitors in an attempt to turn them into clients.Spread across two floors, more than 200 vendors competed at Beijing's Olympic-sized wedding expo for the attention -- and, more importantly, the wallets -- of thousands of young couples.Everything was on sale at a discount, but even a rough calculation on site pointed to the soaring cost of getting married in China.The total bill could easily exceed $20,000 -- an unimaginable sum just a few years ago -- counting a pair of rings, a bridal gown, a banquet, a photo shoot and a professional planner.In the United States, the average cost of a wedding -- excluding a honeymoon -- has a similar price tag of $25,200, according to the latest figure released by the Wedding Report, a market research firm.Although rapid economic growth has brought rising incomes, the average Chinese still makes only a fraction of their American counterpart.Government statistics show the annual disposable income for 2014 was only $3,283 per person in China.The ballooning cost of weddings has spurred a multi-billion-dollar industry, but also put a heavy burden on the more than 10 million couples marrying every year in the world's most populous nation, especially those who already feel financially strained trying to buy their first home and car.Faced with a deep-rooted cultural preference for marriage, however, young Chinese preparing to tie the knot admit that cutting back is not always an option."It's a once-in-a-lifetime event -- so I have to show my commitment to her and her parents through the wedding," explained Wang Di, 23, who was looking for good deals at the expo even though he and his girlfriend don't plan to walk down the aisle for another two years."We may not care that much about the ceremony -- but the parents and other relatives do."Frustrated with family pressure, some rebellious Chinese couples have chosen to enter so-called "naked marriages" with no houses, no cars, no weddings -- and sometimes no rings.While the public seems to appreciate the philosophy of true love trumping everything else, most respondents in repeated surveys still reject the notion of disavowing all traditional trappings of marriage.Increasingly, though, less radical -- but more creative and affordable -- ideas are gaining popularity in big cities.At a courtyard house in suburban Beijing one recent Saturday, the dress code was casual, but everyone appeared to be having some serious fun at the bride and groom's "do-it-yourself" wedding. On stage, the bride had already kicked off her high-heels.The venue was the couple's home -- rented for only $2,500 a year from a local farmer. The decoration that emphasized fresh flowers and entertainment -- featuring a DJ and a band -- were both courtesy of their artistic friends.Adorning the brick walls were various home-made movie-style posters starring the bride and groom, including one showing them laughing in bed with the phrase "mad love" in bold yellow lettering splashed across the red duvet covering their bodies."Almost every wedding now goes through the same drill and I don't want that," said bride Zhang Yueyue, a marketing manager at an arts magazine."I think letting everyone have fun is the most important thing. Many Chinese weddings now are more about flaunting wealth and letting parents have 'face' through extravagance."Counting catering and tailor-made traditional Chinese dresses, Zhang and her artist husband spent less than $2,000 on their big day.With their modest incomes, the newlyweds agreed that saving from the wedding meant more money to start their married life together.Amid loud cheers and applause in the courtyard, some of the couple's guests already felt inspired."My budget won't be high either," said Zhao Mengsha, a colleague and friend of the bride who is planning her own summer wedding. "I just want a big party with some entertainment -- and most importantly lots of alcohol."That definitely sounds like a winning formula for a special occasion.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615013730-china-wedding-cost-jiang-pkg-00001710-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="africa">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/africa/sleeping-beauty-2000-year-old-remains/index.html</url>
        <titulo>'Sleeping beauty': 2,000-year-old remains found in biblical city</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T10:52:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Daisy Carrington, for CNN</autor>
        <texto>(CNN)It was the Queen of Sheba that first drew Louise Schofield -- an archaeologist and former curator at the British Museum -- to the Gheralta plateau in northern Ethiopia. She'd heard tell of a 20-foot stone stele carved with an inscription and a symbol often linked to the biblical queen: a sun and crescent moon."The story of the Queen of Sheba has a central place in the heart of all Ethiopians, so I became interested in the story myself," she recalls (Sheba is thought to be located in parts of Ethiopia).It was this initial visit that ultimately led her to discover the 2,000-year-old remains of a character she fondly refers to as "sleeping beauty."The grave was discovered at the stone stele, in an area that was once part of the ancient kingdom of Aksum, which today encompasses Ethiopia and Eritrea. Inside, Schofield's team found the skeleton of a woman posed in a resting position, with her chin laid gently on one hand. A Roman-era bronze mirror was placed before her face. The corpse was surrounded with glass vessels (to catch the tears of the dead), as well as a bronze cosmetics spoon and a lump of kohl eyeliner."She must have been very wealthy, and probably well-loved to be placed in this position, and judging by all the items of finery around her," surmised Schofield.The dig also uncovered several other graves, all of which had several bodies buried beneath. In some, she found the remains of large warriors clad who each wore an iron bangle."We think they were warriors from a battle," she says.The unusual find suggests trade between Rome and Aksum started at least 200 years earlier than previously believed.As the dig is less than a month old, there's still a lot of information yet to come in about this restful lady. A bone expert wasn't able to ascertain her age at the time of death because the pelvis -- which usually provides a close approximation -- had been consumed by termites. Schofield hopes that analysis of the teeth will provide some answers."There was something very personal about the way she was lying," Schofield says. The remains were also found surrounded by clay containers that likely contained food or drink (these have also been sent off for analysis)."The food, drink and cosmetics were all presumably left for her to use in the afterlife. She was pre-Christian and that's how people buried their dead then," says Schofield.Shofield has a bit of the Midas touch when it comes to extraordinary finds. She also recently uncovered a Roman-era perfume flask in the same cemetery, although by chance. The archaeologist is also the director of London-based NGO The Tigray Trust, and the item was first brought to her attention by a local farmer she knew through the organization."I had been showing around a member of the Peace Corps who had been working in a nearby town (around the site), and we'd been out in the blazing sun for 8 hours, when a farmer I knew said his friend found something old, and he'd been keeping it for me," she recalls."I was apologizing to the Peace Corps guy. I told him, 'it could be an old coffee pot, but you never know, it could be the Queen of Sheba's perfume flask.'"</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612143534-ethiopia-archaeology-excavation-sleeping-beauty-super-169.jpeg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="africa">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/africa/nigeria-illegal-gin/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Nigeria's illegal gin makers find there's a thirst for their potent brew</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T11:59:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Christian Purefoy, CNN</autor>
        <texto>Lagos, Nigeria (CNN)The chisel cuts deep into the palm tree, the fruit flies buzz eagerly, and a white sap slowly drips out into the bucket held by Nigerian gin maker Peter Gabriel. He's collecting the unique ingredient to Nigerian gin -- the palm sap.The bucket fills with the palm sap and drowned fruit flies. Gabriel replaces the full bucket with an empty one and climbs back down the tree. Now he needs to turn his sap into gin."Nigerians like their alcohol, everyone likes alcohol," says Gabriel as he points to his makeshift distillery, situated on the edge of a palm forest, an hour's drive outside of Lagos.The distilling process is simple and illegal.The sap is first mixed with sugar and left to ferment for seven days in sealed blue barrels. Rusted oil drums are then placed over a hot fire and the fermented alcohol poured in. The alcohol evaporates, passes down small pipes through a vat of cold water where it condenses and then drips out into a bucket as a clear, refined gin -- or "Ogogoro" as it's called locally.The government agency that regulates alcohol production and sales in Nigeria insists any product processed with chemicals and labeled for sale must be licensed. But local distillers like Gabriel are largely ignored by the authorities."This one we produce is done in a local way and nothing will happen to you because we source if from the tree," explains Gabriel. "The one others produce is a chemical one and if you take that one, it will cause harm to your body."In the last few months, there has been a spate of mass deaths from drinking poisoned local gin. In Rivers state, in Nigeria's Niger Delta region, over 38 people are thought to have died after drinking at a local gin joint.The problem is that often the alcohol is laced with chemicals, like methanol, to increase the longevity and taste.NAFDAC, Nigeria's Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control, has announced a nationwide ban on the consumption of local gin."We are also warning members of the public to avoid the consumption of all kinds of locally produced spirits, unregistered bitters and related drinks for now," NAFDAC said in a statement.But it has had little impact on the streets, where Nigerians often use Ogogoro not only to help them relax, but also believe it has medicinal effects.At Gabriel's small distillery, with his five friends, he says he can make up to 400 liters of gin a day. And market women still come with their jerry cans to be filled."I make it strong, because if you don't make it strong, people won't come to buy," says Gabriel.The smoke rises in a haze above the distillery, and there is a sweet smell of palm sap in the air. Gabriel and his colleagues sit and play checkers in the humidity.As one of the buckets fills, Gabriel stands from his checkers game for the final stop -- the taste test. He takes a swig from a small bottle, shakes his head and smiles.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150615114038-nigeria-gin-filling-drums-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="europe">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/freedom-project-misery-trail-children/index.html</url>
        <titulo>How children are trafficked into Europe</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T20:38:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Nima Elbagir, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>CNN Freedom Project investigates human trafficking route from Africa to Europe</highlights>
        <highlights>Some boys who made treacherous trip die; others wish they had never left home</highlights>
        <highlights>Boys who found safety in Italy say there is an endless supply of other children dreaming of getting to Europe</highlights>
        <texto>Sicily, Italy (CNN)The 13-year-old boy looks off into the distance. He is slight of build with pale, almost yellowy eyes. When you see him you feel as if he has seen far too much already.He is carrying a burden far too heavy for his age -- but despite his ordeal so far, smuggled across continents from Africa to Europe, and now living in a care home, his future could be far worse depending which route he takes next.A CNN investigation spent months retracing the smuggling route from Egypt to Italy. Speaking to social workers and authorities, children and parents, there is evidence that many of the children were smuggled into Italy by the same criminal networks, who once they are in country, use them for illegal activities.The Egyptian government agency charged with advising lawmakers on child protection matters told CNN that they believe in some cases the parents are guilty of trafficking, paying for their own vulnerable children to be smuggled so far from home in the hope of securing the family's future.We were interviewing this Egyptian boy and his friends in the picturesque piazza of a small Sicilian town.They came over to Italy together on an Egyptian smuggler ship. He was 12 at the time and crammed in with hundreds of others.He says his parents paid 35,000 Egyptian pounds (about $4,500) for the privilege, never guessing what it would really be like -- tossed around for nine days, surrounded by vomit, and scared, uncertain what would meet them on shore.I asked him what he would say to all the boys back at home, hoping to follow in his footsteps. He said he would warn them not to come but he also said he knew they wouldn't listen."Why would they? I didn't," he says. "Everyone does what their mind tells them. They won't take what we say."I asked if, having suffered so much, he'd make the journey again? "What can I do? Yes. The burden back home is still the same."Italian authorities say he is one of more than 1,000 young Egyptians sheltered in 100 Italian care homes now dotting the Sicilian countryside.The cobbled streets and 17th Century architecture is a very long way from the Nile Delta villages many of the boys have come from.I asked one of his friends if he calls his parents and what he tells them about their lives here, and if he's told them how close to death he came."I tell them nothing, just pleasantries and ask for their prayers. What difference would it make? They need me to make money."These boys tell us their parents went in to debt to raise the fare for their crossing. They saw it as an investment in what they hope will be a better future for the whole family. The children are expected to find work as soon as they can and start sending money home.Here at the care home, that's not possible so thousands of children are disappearing from the Italian social care networks.Italy's Ministry of Labor told us almost 4,000 Egyptian children disappeared from the care system.All the Italian authorities we spoke to who work with these children told us the pressure on the children would be unbearable even for an adult. They fear the consequences to their parents if the smugglers didn't get their money in full, or if the gamble doesn't pay off having sold what little of value they have.The missing children can't work legally. Social workers tell us that too often the children turn to drugs, even prostitution, to get by.Another boy we meet at the home asks me wistfully about Rome, which Italian authorities say is where so many of the disappeared head to.I told him Rome is dangerous for children on their own, especially on the streets. I told him the stories we'd heard from the Egyptian teenagers we'd met in Rome -- the exploitation and the homesickness.The Egyptian children in Rome tell stories of friends selling themselves on street corners -- but they sound suspiciously like they were speaking about themselves.I told him it's better to do it all the legal way and better for him to get an education.He listened politely until I'd finished then told me: "Better to be dead than useless."Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612102237-1-migrants-journey-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="china">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/10/china/china-armpit-hair-gender-equality/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Chinese feminists show off armpit hair in photo contest</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-10T16:01:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Wilfred Chan and Shen Lu, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>More than 40 Chinese feminists upload photos of their armpit hair</highlights>
        <highlights>Organizer says hair issue represents principle of gender equality</highlights>
        <texto>Beijing (CNN)In the fight against domestic violence and gender inequality, Chinese feminists have opened up a new battlefront: Their armpits.They ask, why should women have to shave their pits when men are never expected to?To subvert the double standard, feminist Xiao Meili, 25, started an armpit hair photo contest on Chinese social network Weibo.Dozens of women have participated, including three of the five feminists briefly arrested in March over a protest for gender equality. The participants sent in selfies and glamor shots with their arms proudly raised, revealing natural hair underneath."Women should have the right to decide how to deal with their bodies, including small details like armpit hair," Xiao tells CNN. "You can choose to shave it, but you shouldn't be forced to do so under the pressure of stereotypes."Six winners will be selected from the photo competition, which ends Wednesday. Prizes include condoms, vibrators and a pedestal urinal that a woman can use while standing.Xiao, who became a feminist in college after reading female authors like Simone de Beauvoir, says the aesthetics of silky smooth armpits didn't become popular in China until around 20 years ago, as American influences swept into the country. Before that, nobody thought showing armpit hair was an issue.As a small child, Xiao recalled her mother's indifference over armpit hair."She said, 'I don't have much of it. Plus it will eventually shed years later. Why would I bother removing it?'"These days, shaving has become the norm for China women -- but it's not right, says Xiao."The media coverage on female celebrities' underarms is disgusting, as if women shouldn't have hair or it's something to be ashamed of, while male celebrities openly show off their armpit hair."As one participant says beneath her photo submission: "I love my armpit hair. It's part of my body. I hope girls can show off their armpit hair without fear."To Xiao, concern over the armpit hair issue isn't trivial -- it's a matter of principle."Some people question why I make a fuss about the hair. They say there are more important issues that need to be solved like domestic violence and sexual assault. I think they are equally important. They're all about fighting for gender equality."Xiao has tackled other issues concerning women.Last year, she walked more than 1,200 miles across China, sending letters to officials in each city she visited to raise awareness of sex abuse in Chinese schools.Before that, she has staged public art performances to protest everything from violence against women to unfair ratios of male-to-female public restrooms.But it hasn't been easy.In March, five of her friends, fellow activists, were detained after planning a protest in Beijing to counter sexual harassment on public transportation.They were only released a month later after news had spread around the world, leading even Hillary Clinton to condemn the arrests.Although China's current regime was founded on values of gender equality -- Mao Zedong banned old practices such as the binding of women's feet, and famously declared "In China, women hold up half the sky," -- women in today's China face violence and discrimination.According to a 2013 U.N. report, over half of men surveyed in China said they had committed an act of violence against a woman, and over one-fifth confessed to raping a woman.At the same time, women face extreme pressure to marry early, or else risk becoming a "leftover woman." Women who remain single, or fall outside beauty standards, are mocked as "manly women" -- sometimes on national television.And women remain underrepresented in leadership fields: No woman has ever reached China's Standing Committee, the country's highest-ranking political body.No matter: Xiao says she is determined to see the fight through."Gender discrimination exists wherever there are people," she says. "Something needs to be done. We want our voices heard."</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150610023403-china-armpit-hair-5-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="africa">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/23/africa/gallery/beekeeping-women-of-cameroon/index.html</url>
        <titulo>From honey to money: Sweet success of Cameroon's women beekeepers</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-10T17:17:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor></autor>
        <texto></texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/141217133010-eleri-griffiths-beekeeper-restricted-horizontal-large-gallery.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="americas">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/14/americas/paraguay-girl-rape-pregnancy/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Paraguay: We're protecting life of pregnant 10-year-old, fetus</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15T04:55:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Kay Guerrero and Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Paraguay says it's "taken all the appropriate measures" to protect a pregnant 10-year-old's life</highlights>
        <highlights>The Inter-American Commission on Human Rights says Paraguay should do more</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Paraguay's foreign ministry says it doesn't need to follow steps recommended by an international human rights committee that weighed in recently on how the country is handling the case of a 10-year-old pregnant girl who was allegedly raped by her stepfather.In a statement released Sunday, the foreign ministry said it rejects a list of demands from the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights about what it should do to protect the life of the girl.Paraguay already "has taken all the appropriate measures to avoid impunity for the wrongful act committed and to ensure the life and safety of this girl and the fetus," the statement said.Last week, the human rights commission, which is part of the Organization of American States, cited recent testimony from U.N. experts saying Paraguay's government had "failed in its responsibility to protect a 10-year old sexual abuse survivor and provide her with critical and timely treatments, including a 'safe and therapeutic' abortion."At issue is Paraguayan law, which bans abortions except in cases where the pregnancy endangers the mother's life. The Paraguayan Ministry of Health has said there's no indication that the health of the girl is at risk.But the human rights commission said that the girl, now 26 weeks pregnant, is facing a serious health situation with a significant possibility of complications. It criticized the Paraguayan government for not releasing enough information about the case and questioned whether the girl and her family were being provided enough information about the situation and the significant medical risks.The mother of the minor has been imprisoned, charged with breaching her care of duty. Last month, police arrested the girl's 42-year old stepfather, accusing him of raping of the child. He denied this accusations.The case has drawn international attention and sparked debate on the largely taboo issue of incest in South America.According to data from UNICEF, in Paraguay, every day two girls from the ages of 10 and 14 give birth to a baby that is the result of sexual abuse.Paraguay's Ministry of Health says that in 2014, over 680 minors from the ages of 10 to 14 reported a pregnancy. Paraguay has a population of 6.7 million.CNN's Rafael Romo and Jason Hanna and journalist Sanie L&#243;pez Garelli contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150501225016-pkg-romo-paraguay-pregnant-10-year-old-00020128-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/10/asia/china-pika-magic-rabbit-new-risk/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Fame poses new risk for China's 'magic rabbit'</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-11T01:44:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Shen Lu, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Few knew about China's "magic rabbit" until pictures went viral this year</highlights>
        <highlights>Rarer than a panda, it now faces a new threat: Human attention</highlights>
        <highlights>Man who discovered species says reserve is needed to protect tiny mammal</highlights>
        <texto>Beijing (CNN)Rarer than a panda, few people knew about the Ili pika until earlier this year when pictures of China's "magic bunny" went viral after being featured in a series of news reports.But now the tiny and endangered mammal is finding out the price of fame.Conservationist Li Weidong, who discovered the species in 1983, lamented the lack of funding for his conservation efforts when first interviewed by CNN in March.He's since been able to raise almost $28,000 on a Chinese crowd-funding website, enough to fund his research and conservation efforts for the next year.But Li told CNN this week that the tiny mammal now faces other threats.People have tried to catch the pika, wanting one as a pet. Companies have offered Li funding to catch the pika and then artificially breed them, Li said."Ili pikas, as alpine animals, can't adapt to the environment at low elevations without special facilities," he said."Would they survive? Their population is already small enough. Human capture will accelerate the extinction."Fearing that cameras might disturb pikas, Li said he has also turned away a dozen more photographers who hoped accompany him on his field research in the Tianshan mountains.Native to the Xinjiang region of northwestern China, there are fewer than 1,000 of these creatures living in the Tianshan mountain range in the region, Li said.Li discovered the pika, formally known as Ochotona iliensis, and named it after his hometown, Ili.A year ago, Li spotted and photographed the elusive creature for the first time since the early 1990s. He estimates its numbers have declined by almost 70% since its discovery.In 2008, the animal was listed as endangered by the International Union for Conservation of Nature but there's no official organization or team dedicated studying or protecting it, according to Li.For years, Li has called for Ili Pika to be listed on China's List of Wildlife under Special State Protection -- part of the country's 1988 Wildlife Protection Law.The appeal seems more urgent now as more people have laid eyes on the it, Li said.Li said he is in negotiation with authorities in Jinghe County, where many Ili Pikas were discovered, for the establishment of a nature reserve to keep people away from the rare animals.In late May, Li led a team of five volunteers to collect video footage from infrared cameras set up last August.Some 30 infrared cameras captured about 16 video clips of the Pika from the two areas over the past 10 months.Li said the video clips showed that pikas communicate with each other through their own urine traces and bodily waste."They can tell by sniffing whether another pika is nearby. If it is a member of the opposite sex, they find a mate. If it is within its own gender, they claim territory."However, Li didn't find any pikas in the two sites where he spotted and photographed the elusive creature in July last year.He said this doesn't mean there are fewer pikas now as footage from one more area is yet to be collected and the cameras only covered half of the census areas.Yet it still worries him, he said."We don't know whether it's because the animals didn't come out during the winter, or they were eaten by natural enemies or they died."To collect more accurate and complete information, Li said he plans to buy more infrared cameras with the recently raised money and set them up in all six areas.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150323112215-china-ili-pika-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="middle-east">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/09/middleeast/iraq-mosul-isis-takeover-anniversary/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Iraqi veteran who fled Mosul a year ago: ISIS will never, ever leave my city</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-10T13:25:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Ben Wedeman, CNN International Correspondent</autor>
        <highlights>CNN's Ben Wedeman and his crew encounter an Iraqi who has seen it all -- war with Iran, invasion of Kuwait</highlights>
        <highlights>Louay Hikmat Shawkat thinks ISIS is permanently entrenched in Mosul</highlights>
        <highlights>Christian families tell CNN of the hardships they've suffered after being driven out of their beloved city</highlights>
        <texto>Baghdad (CNN)We had just finished up our shoot in Al-Makasib Girls' Elementary School in Baghdad's Saadoun neighbourhood and were loading the gear into the car when a man sitting in a wheelchair across the courtyard beckoned to me."Come, talk to me, too," he said.He introduced himself as Louay Hikmat Shawkat, Iraqi Army veteran of the war with Iran and then the 1991 Kuwait war, refugee from Mosul and a self-described translator of English, French, "Canadian" and "Yugoslavian."Given that the latter two aren't languages, and his English was a tad scratchy, I was intrigued.We were visiting the school to talk to its current "residents" -- 48 Christian families who had fled Mosul when ISIS took over a year ago. Mosul, in northern Iraq and one of the nation's largest cities, is about 405 kilometers (about 250 miles) from the capital of Baghdad. But for these internal refugees, it might as well be a world away.I asked Louay, who is 60, when he thought he might be able to return home."Take it out of your mind that ISIS is going to leave Mosul," he insisted, gesturing with his hand as if he were pulling a thread out of his head.The chances he and his wife will someday return to their home in the Mosul suburb of Hamdaniya, he said, are "one in a hundred. One in a million!"Louay said he suffers from diabetes, but he insists on lighting up another cigarette in his nicotine-stained fingers "because I get upset whenever I speak about "Da'ish", the Arabic acronym for ISIS.ISIS, he said, "is an illness. It's impossible to cure. Cancer can be cured, tuberculosis can be cured. Almost every illness can be cured, but not this one."His diabetes causes him to suffer from dizziness whenever he stands up. "If I were well," he vows, "I would go fight them myself."Like everyone else I spoke with at the school, he is desperate to leave Iraq, but his attempts to apply for asylum have come to naught. His last hope, he told me with a mischievous grin, is an old Canadian girlfriend in Montreal.In the school's makeshift kitchen, I met Linda Jannan, who was busy with the washing up.She fled Mosul with her husband and three children in August, first going to Dohuk, in Iraqi Kurdistan, where they spent six months in a tent in a refugee camp.A thin women in her 30s with the dark circles under her eyes, she also was desperate to leave Iraq."We are finished," she told me. "Our future, our children, our men have been destroyed. We're too afraid to go out and find work. If only someone outside Iraq will help us find a solution, let us emigrate. We have no hope left."She and her husband had applied to asylum in the United States and Germany, but they were rejected because they have no close relatives in either country.Over the past few months, these refugees have been visited by a variety of reporters. And it's clear their patience is wearing thin."What's the point of all this talk?" one man asked me, after declining my request for an on-camera interview. "We talk, we talk, and nothing happens," he snapped.Firyal Abdel Kareem, who was sharing the kitchen with Linda Jannan, is at her wits' end. She spent the winter months in a windy tent in Zakho, near the Turkish border, and is now suffering from Baghdad's sweltering summer heat."Find a solution for us," she told me, "it's enough. We are tired.""Either they take us out of here, or send us home. Do we have to stay in this school, or in a tent?"I've been covering Iraq since 1994. I covered the impact of the draconian international sanctions imposed on the country after Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait. I covered the U.S.-led invasion in 2003 and the messy, bloody aftermath. And now I'm back covering the war against ISIS.I'm lucky. I come and go as I please. For the people in this school, there is no such luxury. Thair Al-Naim, his wife and their three young sons left behind a relatively comfortable life in Mosul last summer. He's now penniless and out of work, all his construction equipment seized and sold by ISIS.Speaking to him in the classroom they now call "home," I sense a deep weariness with a life that, for too long, has been fraught with violence and fear."Since the fall of Saddam," he sighs, "all we've had is war after war, and now we have Da'ish."CNN's Hamdi Alkhshali contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150609185459-iraq-isis-mosul-anniversary-wedeman-pkg-00012918-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/28/asia/china-space-mckenzie/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Chinese astronaut calls for cooperation, access to International Space Station</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-29T04:21:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By David McKenzie, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>CNN obtains exclusive interview with the three-person crew of the Shenzhou-10 mission</highlights>
        <highlights>Commander Nie Haisheng calls for greater international cooperation</highlights>
        <highlights>Analysts believe China's space program could become a world leader</highlights>
        <texto>Beijing (CNN)China wants greater cooperation with other nations in space, particularly the United States, the country's most experienced astronaut has told CNN in an exclusive interview.Fifteen nations including the United States, Russia and Japan cooperate on International Space Station missions, but China's involvement has always been a non-starter because of longstanding resistance from U.S. legislators."As an astronaut, I have a strong desire to fly with astronauts from other countries. I also look forward to going to the International Space Station," Commander Nie Haisheng told CNN."...Space is a family affair, many countries are developing their space programs and China, as a big country, should make our own contributions in this field."The comments came during a wide-ranging and exclusive interview with the three-person crew of the Shenzhou-10 mission inside Space City, the center of China's space program, near Beijing last month.In 2011, Congress passed an act to bar NASA from having any bilateral contact with individuals of the Chinese space program because of national security fears."Every time it gets mentioned at all anywhere near Congress, it gets shut down immediately," space analyst Miles O'Brien told CNN."There is tremendous skepticism there about China. It is viewed as a foe, it is viewed as a government that seeks to take our intellectual property -- our national secrets and treasure."In a white paper released Tuesday, China said that outer space had become an area of "strategic competition.""The Chinese government has always advocated the peaceful use of outer space, it opposes space weaponization and an arms race in outer space. This position will not be changed," Wang Jin, a spokesman for the Ministry of Defense, said.A recent report for the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission said China's improving space capabilities had "negative sum consequences for U.S. military security."But Nie discounted those fears."The United States and Russia started their space programs early. They are the pioneers," he said.He says foreign astronauts are welcome to visit China's own space station once it is launched.The Chinese expect to finish their space station by 2022 -- around the time International Space Station runs out of funding, potentially leaving China as the only country with a permanent presence in space.China launched its manned space program in 1992. It initially borrowed and bought a great deal of Russian technology, primarily by replicating their Soyuz space craft -- which they dubbed the Shenzhou.But it has been steadily checking off the boxes in manned space flight. In 2003, it put its first man in space. In 2008, it completed its first space walk.And in 2013 Nie and his crew completed the country's longest space mission to date and twice docked with the Tiangong-1 space lab.With support from the highest echelons of the ruling Chinese Communist Party and exceptionally deep pockets, most analysts believe China's space program could become a world leader."I think in the end -- tortoise versus hare style, they will probably win," said O'Brien.In October last year, China launched its most ambitious unmanned space mission to date: to orbit the moon and then return to Earth.Nicknamed "Xiaofei," or "Little Flyer" on Chinese social networks, the unmanned orbiter traversed 840,000 kilometers on its eight-day mission that saw it round the far side of the moon and take some incredible pictures of Earth and the moon together, the state-run Xinhua news agency reported.It then successfully re-entered the Earth's atmosphere and parachuted down to the surface in Inner Mongolia.Wu Yanhua, vice director of China's State Administration of Science, Technology and Industry for National Defense, said at the time the successful test mission has gathered a lot of experimental data and laid "a solid foundation for future missions."While China hasn't committed to it, many analysts think it wants to put a man on the moon.However, when asked, Commander Nie won't be drawn on whether this is the ultimate goal of the country's space program."For the next step, the focus is Tiangong-2 and then we will do more preparatory work for the space station."</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150528200842-inside-china-space-program-mckenzie-erin-00004929-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="us">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/asia/gallery/china-nail-houses/index.html</url>
        <titulo>China's 'nail houses': The homeowners who refused to budge</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-01T10:04:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor></autor>
        <texto>In China, they're known as "nail houses" -- homes where owners refuse to accept compensation offered by road builders and developers in exchange for the demolition of their property. The dwellings stand like a nail that refuses to be hammered down -- a not uncommon phenomenon as some homeowners resist dispossession of their land or hold out for more money.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519104533-01-china-nail-house-0519-restricted-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="americas">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/03/americas/architect-3d-prints-luxury-estate/index.html</url>
        <titulo>The luxury 3D printed estate set to be made from sand, dust and gravel</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-03T12:47:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Eoghan Macguire, CNN</autor>
        <texto>(CNN)There's already a 3D-printed house being built in the Netherlands. In China, 3D-printed mansions are reportedly on the rise.Now, a 3D printed estate featuring a swimming pool, jacuzzi, car port and 2,400 square foot house could be coming to a sleepy plot of land in upstate New York.The ambitious project is being undertaken by New York City architect Adam Kushner, alongside partners including 3D-printing pioneer Enrico Dini and his D-Shape firm.Kushner told CNN that surveying has already begun with excavation work also set to commence soon.The swimming pool and jacuzzi are penciled in to be completed by December 2015 while construction of the house is expected to continue until the end of 2017, he says.But the project hinges on getting the giant 3D printer, which will be used to produce the digitally designed building blocks of the estate on-site, into the country.The device is currently in Italy after it was originally being built for a project partly funded by the Italian defense agencies. Military clearance is now required before the green light is given to export the printer to the United States, Dini says.The delay in receiving this clearance is part of the reason the project has been held up since it was first announced back in August 2014."We are now waiting (for) permission to borrow the printer (from the military)," Dini says. "If I had another printer I'd send it there tomorrow, but unfortunately we don't have and must wait."Whatever the import-export issues, Kushner says he sees the estate project as a test of D-Shape's printer technology and its distinctive method.This practice entails collecting sand, dust and gravel on site and mixing them with a magnesium-based binding agent to produce the 3D-printed building blocks required to piece the estate together. According to literature on the D-Shape website, the material produced by the printer is "similar to marble" in its constitution.This technique is vastly different from other 3D-printing methods, Kushner says, and enables the production of many more "sculptural forms" that simply aren't possible with other systems.If D-Shape can prove its technology works and is efficient for a project of this size, Kushner believes it could lead to all manner of possibilities in architecture and construction. Not only could it be faster and safer than existing construction methods, he says, it could also end up being cheaper, more streamlined and of higher quality.And although the 3D-printed estate is something only the very wealthiest would be able to replicate, Kushner sees D-Shape's construction methods benefiting the less fortunate as well."This will serve as a way of using our project to ... pave the way for more humanitarian purposes that we see as the highest and best use for our technology," he says."If we can build a simple pool house, I can print thousands of refugee housings. If I can build a pool, I can print underwater reefs (which he says D-Shape has already done before) to repair bridges, piers and infrastructures."Integrating progressively more advanced 3D-printing methods into the construction industry has been a topic that has generated many eye-catching headlines in recent years.The process of contour crafting -- where large 3D printers are assembled on a building site (much like what will happen on Kushner's estate) and programmed to construct pre-designed concrete structures and their relevant sub-components -- was put forward by Dr. Behrokh Khoshnevis of the University of Southern California as far back as 2009.Khoshnevis told industry website 3DPrint.com earlier this year that the first printers large enough for his version of contour crafting should become available within the next two years. He added that the method could even be used to build high-rise structures within ten years.Chinese firm WinSun seemed to take inspiration from Khoshnevis' methods when they claimed to have 3D printed a mansion and six-story tower block in the city of Suzhou, eastern China earlier this year.Meanwhile, in the Netherlands, DUS Architects continue to piece together a 3D-printed house using its "KamerMaker" machine. Company co-founder Katherine De Wit described the DUS technique as being a potentially valuable tool that could be added to those already used to build homes.Other experts, however are more cautious about the immediate potential of 3D-printing technology in the construction industry.In an interview with CNN in 2014, Dr. Phil Reeves, managing director of UK-based 3D-printing consultancy and research firm Econolyst, described 3D-printing a house on site like that planned by DUS as counter to existing building techniques which are already relatively efficient.Then there are other fast-developing building methods like prefabricated construction which entails manufacturing components in a factory before transporting and rapidly piecing them together on a building site.Chinese firm Broad Sustainable Building claimed to have used this method to piece together a 57-story skyscraper in just 19 days earlier this year.For Kushner, however, the benefits of large-scale 3D-printing are many and will likely increase as the technology becomes more advanced."This is not superfluous, nor a lazy architects idyll," he says. "I think it's as important as the automobile was in changing the design of cities or how the printing press altered communication.""Why? Because it democratizes construction and architecture and puts it into everyone's hands, just like the camera phone made everyone a photographer. Not everyone is good at it but everyone can become one."</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150526160059-3d-printed-house-pool-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="middle-east">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/20/middleeast/iraq-isis-timeline-since-u-s-withdrawal/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Iraq: How did we get here?</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-22T17:29:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Michael Martinez, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Iraq becomes a 'sad story' since U.S. troops withdrew in late 2011, analyst says</highlights>
        <highlights>ISIS extremists now control Ramadi and Mosul, two major cities in Iraq</highlights>
        <highlights>A U.S.-led coalition returns to Iraq, to conduct airstrikes only</highlights>
        <texto>(CNN)Iraq roils in a maelstrom: ISIS now controls Ramadi, a new prime minister is in charge, Shiite-Sunni bloodshed flows, and a U.S.-led coalition is back, this time executing airstrikes in Iraq.The saga of Iraq is, as an analyst put it, "a rather straightforward but sad story" since the U.S. military left the country at the end of 2011, only to find itself returning in a smaller way.The fall of Ramadi to ISIS this week strikes many as a milestone because the city is the capital of Iraq's biggest province and because U.S. troops heroically fought insurgents there in the mid-2000s.Some politicians feel the U.S. withdrawal of troops was a mistake, though public opinion favored it then."An ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure. Too late for that now," said Paul Salem of the nonpartisan Middle East Institute.Iraq's problems are bigger than Ramadi: its second largest city, Mosul, is now ISIS' capital, and Iraq still struggles with self-governance, politically and militarily.Here are events since late 2011 that help explain Iraq's ongoing conflict:After almost 4,500 Americans were killed and more than 30,000 injured since 2003 when the United States invaded Iraq, President Barack Obama orders the withdrawal of all troops.The President welcomes them home."The war in Iraq will soon belong to history," Obama says. "Your service belongs to the ages."We are leaving behind a sovereign, stable and self-reliant Iraq, with a representative government that was elected by its people," the President also says.The return of U.S. soldiers fulfills Obama's campaign pledge in 2008 to end the war.In Iraq, the day is celebrated as "Iraq Day."Tension grows between Iraq's Shiite and Sunni sects.Their blood feud reaches back decades.The Shiites control the central government under Prime Minister Nuri al-Maliki, and Sunni Vice President Tariq al-Hashimi is accused of terrorism by the top judicial committee. The body alleges al-Hashimi's security detail carried out 150 attacks between 2005 and 2011.Al-Hashimi dismisses the accusations as politics, noting the judicial committee is controlled by Shiites, and his party threatens to boycott parliament.Some good news, relatively speaking.Violence kills 112 people, the lowest monthly death toll since the U.S-led invasion in 2003, officials say.It's a good sign for the country's ability to maintain security.Iraq also hosts an Arab League summit, a gathering that signals the political emergence of postwar democratic Iraq.But it doesn't last long: By July, violence reaches a nearly two-year peak, with 325 deaths that month.Prime Minister al-Maliki comes under increasing criticism but he survives the threat of a no-confidence vote by parliament.President Jalal Talabani announces that there is not enough support for the vote.Al-Maliki's opponents accuse him of monopolizing power.Later, Osama al-Nujaifi, speaker of parliament, presses efforts to oust al-Maliki and says the Prime Minister will be asked to appear before the governing body.Al-Hashimi, Iraq's top Sunni politician, is given a death sentence in absentia, and he lashes out at the country's top Shiite leader, Prime Minister al-Maliki."The verdict is unjust, political and illegitimate and I will not acknowledge it," al-Hashimi tells reporters in Ankara, Turkey, where he has been living since fleeing Iraq five months earlier."To my dear people, I say, make sure that al-Maliki and those who stand behind him don't get what he wishes. Because they want sectarian strife," al-Hashimi says.He remains in exile.The anniversary of the U.S. troops' departure is celebrated as "Day of Sovereignty."But the political climate remains divisive.Days before the anniversary, thousands of Sunnis protest in the streets of Anbar province, a region key to trade with Jordan and Syria, and the Sunnis denounced al-Maliki's order to arrest the bodyguards of Finance Minister Rafaie Esawi, a Sunni.Sunnis and ethnic Kurds accuse al-Maliki and his Shiite political party of cutting them out of the political process, an allegation that comes as U.S. lawmakers raise concerns about Iraq strengthening its ties with Shiite-dominated Iran.Syria, torn by civil war, increasingly loses control of its border with Iraq.Concern looms that Sunni militants on both sides of the border will be capable of challenging governments in both Damascus and Baghdad and control a no-man's land.This foreshadows the rise of ISIS, which began as a splinter group of al Qaeda. The Islamic State in Iraq and Syria dreams of creating an Islamic state, or caliphate, across the Sunni areas of Iraq and in Syria.The month also marks the 10th anniversary of the U.S.-led coalition invading Iraq and later ousting authoritarian leader Saddam Hussein.Iraq sees the deadliest month in the last five years since sectarian violence peaked in 2006 and 2007: 1,057 Iraqis are killed and 2,326 more are wounded in acts of terrorism and violence.Al Qaeda in Iraq was declared "on the run" before the U.S. pullout, but now it and other Sunni extremist groups grow stronger as the Shiite-led government fails to bring Sunnis into the political fold. Iraq's Sunni population claims that it is targeted by government forces and grows more alienated and disenfranchised.Al Qaeda in Iraq has expanded into Syria under the umbrella of "Al Qaeda in Iraq and the Levant (Syria)."Questions arise on whether Prime Minister al-Maliki can hold Iraq together against a rising insurgency.ISIS grows. It was known as al Qaeda in Iraq, but now the acronym "ISIS" appears more in news accounts as the militant group seeks to create a single Islamic state in Syria, Iraq and even Lebanon.ISIS continues to exploit a security vacuum across Iraq. It and government troops battle in Ramadi and Falluja -- famous battlegrounds from the days when U.S. forces occupied the country.U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry says the United States will help the Iraqi government in the battle against al Qaeda-linked fighters in western Iraq, but he stresses that America won't send troops.ISIS fighters are "the most dangerous players in the region," Kerry says.Al Qaeda and ISIS divorce, so to speak.Al Qaeda's central leadership says ISIS "is not a branch of the al Qaeda group."ISIS rejects al Qaeda's leadership.One thing is clear: the jihadists are infighting.ISIS seizes Mosul in northern Iraq and threatens a march on Baghdad. Another northern city, Samarra, is besieged.A strategic border crossing in the western province of Anbar, the largest geographically in Iraq, falls to ISIS fighters. They also take four small towns.The speed of Iraq's deterioration surprises U.S. officials.Obama says he's prepared to send military advisers to Iraq but not in a combat role.Obama authorizes "targeted airstrikes" against ISIS outposts in northern Iraq as the militants advance to Irbil, known as a regional capital for the country's ethnic Kurds.About 130 Marines and special operations forces are sent to northern Iraq to help tens of thousands of the minority Yazidi people trapped in the mountains by ISIS, who vow to kill them. "Very specifically, this is not a combat boots on the ground operation," U.S. Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel says.ISIS is "a credible alternative to al Qaeda," a U.S. intelligence official tells CNN.ISIS shocks the world by releasing its first beheading video of an American -- the victim is journalist James Foley -- and threatens the life of another American captive if Obama doesn't end military operations in Iraq. Other beheading videos will follow later.Meanwhile, Prime Minister al-Maliki withdraws his candidacy for a third term as pressure mounts abroad and at home for him to step down.Replacing him will be Haider al-Abadi, who, like al-Maliki, is a member of the Islamic Dawa Party, one of the country's biggest Shiite political blocs.Obama announces the United States will launch airstrikes against ISIS targets in Syria, too.The United States underestimated ISIS and overestimated the Iraqis' military will to fight, Obama says.U.S. Secretary of State Kerry adds the expanded military campaign will take time to degrade ISIS."There's definitely a second day and there will be a third and more. This is going to go on," Kerry says.Several other countries will join the U.S. airstrikes against ISIS in Iraq and Syria.Obama asks Congress to formally authorize the use of the U.S. military in the war against ISIS, but he doesn't call for ground troops in Iraq or Syria.Iraqi forces, joined by Shiite militiamen, enjoy a victory: They retake the city of Tikrit from ISIS.ISIS scores a victory whose symbolism resonates with Americans: After months of clashes with Iraqi and allied forces, ISIS takes control of the key Iraqi city of Ramadi after government security forces pull out of a military base on the west side.Ramadi is 70 miles west of Baghdad.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519163626-orig-ramadi-explainer-pleitgen-00011508-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/18/asia/china-families-belongings/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Stunning images show Chinese families and everything they own</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-18T12:26:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Shen Lu, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>A Chinese photographer has spent a decade taking pictures of families and their entire belongings</highlights>
        <highlights>Most photos show a variety of landscapes and lifestyles, along with their neatly lined up possessions</highlights>
        <highlights>His goal is to tell the stories of those who have not been able to enjoy the success of China's economic boom</highlights>
        <texto>Beijing (CNN)For more than a decade, Chinese photographer Ma Hongjie has asked dozens of families across the country to empty their homes and pose in front of everything they own.His goal is to tell the stories of those who have been bypassed by China's economic boom -- the people living on the bottom rung of society that haven't enjoyed the fruits of the country's transformation."The possessions are not even wealth. It's just their lives -- showing how the grassroots try to make a living," said Ma, a photo editor at Chinese National Geography magazine.While the mesmerizing images show a variety of landscapes, lifestyles and cultures, what's most striking is their similarity -- the neatly lined up possessions are mostly daily essentials and tools of trade. Their owners appear proud yet humble.Almost all of Ma's subjects are rural families. He has asked richer families living in cities to participate, but they weren't willing to take part in the project, he said.They possess a lot more, and were afraid of the repercussions of showcasing their wealth, Ma explained."Yet grassroots were fully at ease showing me whatever they have," he said. "They'd first feel wary about my request, but when I showed the samples they thought it was interesting."Although China now is the second largest economy after the United States, it is also home to the second largest number of poor people in the world, according to the World Bank.Almost 100 million people lived below the national poverty line of $1 a day in 2012.In his book, which is due to be published later in May, Ma gives the back stories of the families he's photographed.The deepest impression the people he profiled has left upon him is their attitude. Powerless, they never demand anything, Ma said."Are they satisfied? No. But they have no choice but to accept whatever happens to them," he added. "But they try to live with however little they possess."Although humbling, it also frustrated him."They suffer from silence."Ma recently revisited the first family he profiled. They lived in a rural town in a mountainous area of Hunan province in southeastern China, back in 2003.To his dismay, nothing had changed in the 10 years since his first visit; their shabby house had become even shabbier, he said.Their sons wanted to get married, but the family couldn't afford to build new homes for them.They had hoped tourism would develop in this old town so that the family would be subsidized for moving out&#8212;then the sons would be able to marry, he said.Similar stories unfolded everywhere Ma traveled.The Sun family live on boats on the Yellow River that winds through China's heartland. Sun Guiyou, who has been traversing the rivers and lakes for his entire life, says his biggest dream is to one day have a permanent house built on the land.Although the family say they are better off since he first photographed them in 2006, nothing much has changed and they haven't been able to build a home on solid ground."The way they make a living doesn't change, they are still fishing," he said."The grandchildren didn't get a good education, or even dropped out of school. You can see them repeating their grandparent's life in the future."Ma said he was stunned by the diversity of cultures and lifestyles he came across and that it was harrowing to witness these traditions erode.Only a few of the local artisans and performers he met said their offspring were willing to carry on their crafts. Instead, they go to the cities and become migrant workers.When he visited a village in Hainan province in 2010, people lived in small huts. On his return years later, the huts had been replaced by brick and cement dwellings built by the government.In response, the villagers had built new huts next to the government subsidized housing instead, because they were not built in a way that suited their lifestyle. Ventilating smoke from how they cooked meals became difficult in those houses."The local government thought living in huts was uncivilized, but they were unique," Ma said. "Why should everything be uniform?"The families he documented also shared a hatred of red tape - they bemoaned interference from the local government. So when the government decided to scrap an ancient tradition of taxing farmers for agricultural produce in 2006, farmers and peasants were thrilled by the news."They simply want to be left alone -- 'Don't make our life so troublesome, let us farm and let us live,' they told me." Ma said.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150517111602-china-possessions-ma-hongjie-43-super-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="africa">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/africa/namibia-rhino-hunt/index.html</url>
        <titulo>Texas hunter bags his rhino on controversial hunt in Namibia</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-21T21:28:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>By Ed Lavandera, CNN</autor>
        <texto>Northern Namibia (CNN)In January 2014, Corey Knowlton bid $350,000 for a permit to hunt and kill a black rhino in Namibia.He won the permit and became a target himself.The hunt is now complete. A rhino is dead.This is how it happened.Windhoek, Namibia -- Knowlton arrived quietly in Namibia to hunt the famed black rhino.Nearly 18 months ago, the Texas hunter bid $350,000 to kill a black rhinoceros in the southern African country of Namibia. The permit was issued by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism and auctioned by the Dallas Safari Club.Since then, Knowlton has faced scathing criticism and death threats as the world reacted to the controversial hunt of one of the world's most endangered species. Knowlton has spent the last year and a half preparing and planning the hunt that is being highly scrutinized by animal welfare groups around the world.He agreed to let our CNN crew document the hunt."At this point, the whole world knows about this hunt and I think it's extremely important that people know it's going down the right way, in the most scientific way that it can possibly happen," Knowlton said after arriving in Africa.Knowlton, 36, from Dallas, wants the world to see that the hunt of such a majestic beast on the African continent is not the work of a bloodthirsty American hunter but a vital component of Namibia's effort to save the animal from extinction.Knowlton's $350,000 will go to fund government anti-poaching efforts across the country. And the killing of an older rhino bull, which no longer contributes to the gene pool but which could harm or kill younger males, is part of the science of conservation, he argues.That's why he says he's doing more to save the black rhino than his critics, and why he wanted us along on this historic hunt.Opponents like the International Fund for Animal Welfare have not been swayed, saying hunting as conservation is a bankrupt notion. "We'll simply never agree with that," fund director Azzedine Downes said. "There's a lot of other things that we can and must do in order to protect these animals."The journey of this hunt will examine the emotional debate raging around the issue of how best to protect endangered species on a continent that is home to some of the most legendary animals on the planet."I think people have a problem just with the fact that I like to hunt," Knowlton said. "I want to see the black rhino as abundant as it can be. I believe in the survival of the species."Northern Namibia -- The hunt sets off with a sunrise flight to the region of Namibia where Knowlton will track a black rhino.There's a great deal of concern about news coverage of the hunt in Namibia. We've been told that when our reports are broadcast around the world that Namibian government officials fear poaching syndicates will use the information to identify the location of other black rhinos.For that reason, we have agreed not to report the specific locations of the hunt. According to animal conservationists, there are approximately 5,000 black rhinos in the wild worldwide today, 2,000 of them in Namibia.Hentie van Heerden is a professional hunter hired by the Namibian government to guide Knowlton on the highly scrutinized hunt of the black rhino.Van Heerden, 40, has an international clientele, mostly from Europe, who come to hunt wild game and the exotic animals of Africa.He was born in Namibia and grew up hunting. The thorn-infested terrain in the north of the country does not faze him. He wears sandals even when he hunts the wildest of animals.The bearded van Heerden has the dry sense of humor of a skilled hunter teaching a journalist what to do if we are to stare down a charging rhino."The aim is to get out of its way without him flattening you," he said. "It's very rare that they come back for seconds and if that is the case, you have to get some more out of its way."Van Heerden says there are a few critics of the black rhino hunt in Namibia, but most people here embrace a culture of hunting."There will always be activists and that's how they make their money," he said. "They have no clout here in Namibia, because people understand hunting."The hunt is sanctioned and monitored by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism. It has identified 18 black rhinos across the country that meet the criteria for being hunted and eliminated.The rhino must be an older rhino that is no longer reproducing and is considered a threat to younger, healthier rhinos.Rhinos are intensely territorial and will often kill each other in gruesome fights.Knowlton is targeting one of four black rhinos at the top of the government list, the ones considered "high priority threats to the herd."But identifying these rhinos in the dense brush and in the heat of a dangerous hunt makes Knowlton uneasy, though he will have the help of local trackers and guides."If it charges at us and we are already sure it's the right one, we are going to kill it," Knowlton said. "If we aren't sure if it's the right one, we are going to try and get out of the way. If we don't feel like we can get out of the way, we got to kill it."That would be the worst-case scenario for Knowlton. For him, the rhino hunt must be carried out flawlessly.Northern Namibia -- Just after sunrise, Knowlton arrives at a watering hole hidden deep in the Namibian brush to start the hunt. Two government trackers have spotted signs of a rhino heading away from the water.The footprint appears fresh. The weathered wrinkles of the rhino's hide are still visible in the print. The intricate details in the sand suggest the tracks are just a few hours old.The government tracker says, based on the footprints, he can tell this animal is probably one of the black rhinos Knowlton has been permitted to hunt, and that the animal is probably no more than 5 miles away.This is where the hunt begins.The trackers move quickly through the thorny bush and tall grasses. They rarely speak. Quick hand signals are all they need to show the path to follow.Silence is vital when you're tracking a black rhino.The hunting party winds its way through the brush. The rhino's footprints suggests the nearly 3,000 pound (1,360 kilogram) beast is meandering, which tells the hunters it does not feel threatened.As the heat of the day intensifies, rhinos will usually find shady areas to take quick naps.The ranger from the ministry who is observing and leading the trackers says the hunting party is gaining ground on the rhino.But the brush is so dense. Knowlton worries that we could stumble across the rhino at any moment and end up face to face."I think people think of it as this docile thing," Knowlton said of his prey. "But you are dealing with an extremely athletic animal that can do whatever it wants to you very quickly."The only sounds are the brushes and scrapes of the hunting party cutting through the thorn-infested bushes of this terrain. It seems like every bush has wicked thorns that rip across our skin and clothing.Rhinos have an intense sense of smell and hearing that alerts them to danger from hundreds of yards away. The winds are swirling in the early afternoon hours and the tracker says the rhino can probably sense our presence and is moving away quickly.Knowlton is more concerned with something else. He's been told there are three rhinos known to inhabit the area he's in, but the Namibian government has only authorized the hunting of two of them.Visibility in the brush around us is down to about 15 feet (4.6 meters.) Knowlton is worried that if the rhino charges through the thick brush that he would only have a split second to decide whether to take the shot.It's becoming too risky. We've spent five hours trekking nearly 6 miles through the brush when Knowlton and his hunting partner decide to call it a day.Killing the wrong rhino, Knowlton said, would be a catastrophic mistake.Last year, one of Knowlton's critics suggested the trophy hunting of a black rhino was like shooting a couch in a living room.This criticism annoys Knowlton endlessly. He's quick to bring it up with a heavy dose of sarcasm."So this is just like hunting a couch? Give me a break," he said. "This isn't easy. It's brutal."On the road to southern Namibia -- Knowlton decides the hunt in the north is too treacherous. The brush is dense and visibility low.That's a dangerous combination for the hunting party and Knowlton knows that killing the wrong rhino will make him an even bigger target of international outrage.He and his hunting guide decide to drive to southern Namibia to target another dangerous black rhino that lives in a region with better visibility.But on the way we hear that rhino has died, probably of natural causes.Northern Namibia -- Knowlton returns to the region that makes him the most nervous. And on this morning, the trails are not strong.The trackers have trouble finding prints leading away from the watering holes where the rhinos drink vast amounts of water.It's clear the rhino hunt will not end today.Northern Namibia -- The morning starts with a startling discovery. Knowlton's professional hunting guide has discovered a camera image showing a rhino at a remote watering hole just before sunrise.The image is stunning. The rhino is more massive than I expected. Its horn is long with a lethal pointed tip. Knowlton spots a large gash in the rhino's ear. It's a crucial identifying mark that tells him instantly this rhino is on the approved government list to be hunted.The hunting party quickly picks up the tracks and disappears into the vicious African bush.The rhino footprints are fresh and light on the sand, telling the trackers the animal is slowly walking, eating grass and taking naps in the shade to avoid the rising sun.Today feels different. There's a sense that just beyond our view we are close to the rhino. The hunting party stops to drink water in the shade of a tree for 20 minutes.When the tracking resumes, Knowlton discovers the spot where the rhino had been resting not moments earlier. You can see the imprint of its wrinkled hide still fresh on the sandy ground.The rhino is close. Knowlton's hands firmly grip his high-powered 500 Nitro Express rifle. Moments later, I see a massive flash of gray leap up over the bushes some 50 feet in front of us. It disappears and you can't tell which direction the rhino is running.It's jarring to see this close how quickly these massive creatures can move.I remember the advice van Heerden, the professional hunting guide, gave me the day before."You can't outrun the rhino," he said. "If it means to dive into a thorn bush to the left or to the right, we need to get out of its way in a big hurry."Now we can't see the rhino, but we know it's close.Van Heerden tells Knowlton, "He's angry. The next time he will charge."Twenty minutes later as the hunting party moves through the brush, I hear a sound I've not heard before during our trek.The rhino is moving around but it's invisible. It's impossible to grasp how such a beast can move like a ghost in the brush.The hunting party moves single file through a tree line. As the last member of the group emerges, he looks to his left and no more than 40 feet away the rhino is there, staring straight at us."There it is!" says the last member in the group.It's a breathtaking sight. But this isn't the time to stand and stare. I cut to one side and the rhino starts charging in my direction."Ed! Get down!" shouts van Heerden.I rush behind Knowlton and his hunting guide."As soon as you dropped below my gun, I could see the whole animal right behind you," Knowlton would tell me later.I turn around and for a quick flash only see the top half of the rhino in front of us. Then four shots explode through the air.The rhino has been hit at least three times.The hunting party then makes the final push to find the rhino. I've lost track of time. This last push might have taken 30 minutes, it might have taken an hour. It was an incredibly emotional experience.A tracker climbs into a tree and spots the rhino in an open field about 100 yards away. Knowlton gets into position and fires the final shots. The black rhino is dead.Knowlton walks up from behind the rhino and when he's certain it's over, he kneels next to it."Any time you take an animal's life it's an emotional thing," Knowlton said.The Namibian government official assures Knowlton it is the rhino on the approved hunting list. The trackers smile with relief and shake hands.I ask Knowlton if he still feels that killing this black rhino was the right thing to do and that it will benefit the future of this endangered species."I felt like from day one it was something benefiting the black rhino," Knowlton reflected just moments after the hunt ended. "Being on this hunt, with the amount of criticism it brought and the amount of praise it brought from both sides, I don't think it could have brought more awareness to the black rhino."CNN's Jason Morris contributed to this report.</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519144717-rhino-hunt-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
    <noticia local="asia">
        <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/asia/north-korean-child-defectors-revisited/index.html</url>
        <titulo>From traitors to poster children: Defectors 'forgiven' by North Korea</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-20T04:45:00.000+01:00</data>
        <autor>Tim Schwarz, CNN</autor>
        <highlights>Missionary couple helped hide young North Korean defectors in China</highlights>
        <highlights>They were caught and sent back, prompting fears for their lives</highlights>
        <highlights>Instead of punishment, the regime decided to send them to school and university</highlights>
        <texto>Pyongyang, North Korea (CNN)Kkot-jebi -- literally "flower swallows" -- sounds poetic, but the reality is much harsher.The North Korean term refers to homeless children, fending for themselves without the support of family or state. The word traces it roots back to the aftermath of the Korean War, an imaginative pronunciation of the Russian word "kochevyi," meaning "wandering," and referring to those displaced by the 1950-53 conflict.During the 1990s, North Korea was hit by several years of famine as disastrous harvests laid waste to the land, killing hundreds of thousands, according to conservative estimates. The country's social safety net was reduced to tatters. Families fell apart. And flower swallows re-emerged in large numbers.Although conditions today are much better, North Korea remains desperately poor. Food is in short supply for a large portion of the population -- and kkot-jebi are still very much in existence.North Korea is one of the most secretive societies in the world. When a CNN team recently visited, our entire schedule was arranged by our official government hosts. Our "minders" accompanied us on every shoot. We had put in certain requests, but we never knew more than a few hours in advance what the next item on our itinerary would be.When we were told to go to a meeting room at our hotel one afternoon, we had no idea who was going to be behind the doors, just something to do with the reality of defectors.When we walked through the doors and saw eight young people sitting on one side of a huge round conference table, we immediately knew who we were to meet.In early summer 2013, the world's media cried foul over the repatriation of a group of nine North Korea children, then aged between 14 and 19, from Laos. They had been picked up by border security as they were being smuggled from China into Laos by South Korean missionaries, in the hope of getting them resettled in South Korea.Pyongyang is not shy about its hatred of defectors. It refers to them in official media as "human scum" and accuses them of criminal acts, lying about their own country for fame and money and abandoning their own families.The decision to return the children was widely condemned. Dire predictions were made about their fate: The children were being sent back to prison; they would face a lifetime of retribution and could even be executed.But here in this room, nearly two years after their return, these former kkot-jebi appear transformed. Four young men dressed in the blue blazers of university students and two boys and two girls in secondary school uniforms, all sat waiting to answer our questions. The ninth member of the group was in a university further away from Pyongyang and could not be brought in at short notice.They were all children between the ages of 12 and 17 when they crossed into China, separately or in small groups. They only met after they arrived at the missionaries' house.We asked why they left -- it was an uncomfortable opening question."We were young," said 17-year-old Ri Gwang Hyok. "We just went to China for fun."Pressed for more detail, Mun Chol, 21, admitted: "Frankly, we had some family difficulties. We had been through a period in our history we call 'the arduous march (the years of famine).' We were not living well. I was young and naive. We were living by the Amnok river, which is at the border. I meant to return home. I was curious."We then asked how many of them had experienced hunger before they left.Four of the eight raised their hands."It was winter. We had preserved food during autumn. But it wasn't enough. Our family was too large," explained Pak Kwang Hyok, 19.Once in China, the children were brought to a house in the border town of Dandong, looked after by a South Korean missionary CNN has called M.J. in previous reports, along with his wife. There, according to M.J., the starving children were transformed. According to the youngsters now, the picture was not so rosy. They said they were kept in the house for a year and a half."The missionary lectured us about freedom," recalled Mun Chol. "But we weren't given any freedom. He forced us to study God and memorize religious books."Of course, the food was good," he added, "but that was our only pleasure. When you have food things seem OK, but a kid needs more than that."Following our encounter with the students, CNN contacted M.J., who asked about their well-being. He says he misses them.While hesitant to say much out of fear for their safety, he insists the students needed his help after fleeing North Korea.China is a historical ally of North Korea, and North Koreans found illegally in the country face deportation if caught. After a year and a half, the missionary decided to move the children to a third country. He chose Laos, on China's southwestern border, from where he hoped he could get them to South Korea.After a harrowing night trek for four hours through the hilly border region, the party were picked up by Laotian police and detained.When they were told they would be sent back to North Korea they were terrified."The missionary said we would be killed if we went back," said Mun Chol. "He told us our families had been killed because we had left our homes."But instead of being punished, they tell us they received special treatment, extra tuition to make up for three years of missed schooling, and are now studying in the best educational establishments in the capital."I was scared," admitted Pak Gwang Hyok. "I had left my home with a guilty conscience and spent time abroad. We had betrayed our country. I thought we would be punished. But now we are studying in the best universities in Pyongyang. Our fears were pretty foolish."Soon after their return, the children appeared on North Korean television to denounce their enticement to defect by South Koreans. Now , more than a year later, they are again on display. They have become poster children for the "benevolence and forgiveness" of the North Korean authorities.There is a huge difference between their lives when they left for China and now. "I feel like a pauper who has become a prince," said Ri Gwang Hyok.But their families have not joined them in Pyongyang, the showcase capital. They remain in the poor border areas and their lives have not changed.When he thinks about what might have happened if he had made it to South Korea, Mun Chol said, "If I had made it, I could have become a traitor -- a bad guy who deserts his family."I could have gone down in history as one of the 'scum of the earth.'"</texto>
        <mediaurl>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519170546-pkg-ripley-north-korea-defectors-00003710-large-169.jpg</mediaurl>
    </noticia>
</noticias>
